.gitkeep
10 Holy Martyrs of Crete (12-23).jpg
100,000 Martyrs of Tbilisi by the Mongols (10-31).jpg
12 Greeks who built the Dormition Cathedral in the Kiev Caves, Far Caves, Lavra (02-14).jpg
14,000 Infants (the Holy Innocents) slain by Herod at Bethlehem (12-29).jpg
1st Saturday of Great Lent The Miracle of the Boiled Wheat (02-28).jpg
1st Sunday of Great Lent Sunday of Orthodoxy (03-01).jpg
26 Monastic Martyrs of Zographou Monastery on Mount Athos (10-10).jpg
26 Monastic Martyrs of Zographou, Mount Athos (09-21).jpg
2nd Sunday of Great Lent St Gregory Palamas (03-08).jpg
3rd Sunday of Great Lent Veneration of the Cross (03-15).jpg
40 Holy Martyrs of Sebaste (03-09).jpg
45 Holy Martyrs at Nicopolis in Armenia (07-10).jpg
4th Sunday of Great Lent St John Climacus (of the Ladder) (03-22).jpg
5th Saturday of Great Lent of the Akathist to the Theotokos (03-28).jpg
5th Sunday of Great Lent St Mary of Egypt (03-29).jpg
6,000 Martyrs of Saint David Gareji Monastery, Georgia (04-26).jpg
7 Holy Maccabee Martyrs (08-01).jpg
7 Holy Youths “Seven Sleepers” of Ephesus (08-04).jpg
9 Kherkheulidze Brothers with their Mother and Sister and Nine Thousand Martyrs of Marabda (08-03).jpg
9 Martyred brothers of Kola Guram, Adarnerse, Baqar, Vache, Bardzim, Dachi, Juansher, Ramaz, and Parsman (02-22).jpg
99 Martyred Fathers of Crete (10-07).jpg
Afterfeast of the Dormition of the Mother of God (08-16).jpg
Afterfeast of the Dormition of the Mother of God (08-18).jpg
Afterfeast of the Dormition of the Mother of God (08-19).jpg
Afterfeast of the Elevation of the Cross (09-15).jpg
Afterfeast of the Elevation of the Cross (09-16).jpg
Afterfeast of the Elevation of the Cross (09-18).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-03).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-04).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-05).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-06).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-07).jpg
Afterfeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-08).jpg
Afterfeast of the Nativity of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (12-28).jpg
Afterfeast of the Nativity of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (12-29).jpg
Afterfeast of the Nativity of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (12-30).jpg
Afterfeast of the Nativity of the Mother of God (09-09).jpg
Afterfeast of the Nativity of the Mother of God (09-11).jpg
Afterfeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-07).jpg
Afterfeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-08).jpg
Afterfeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-09).jpg
Afterfeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-11).jpg
Afterfeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-12).jpg
Afterfeast of the Transfiguration of our Lord (08-07).jpg
Afterfeast of the Transfiguration of our Lord (08-08).jpg
Afterfeast of the Transfiguration of our Lord (08-09).jpg
anastasis-resurrection.jpg
andrew-first-called.jpg
annonciation.jpg
Antipascha Saint Thomas Sunday (04-19).jpg
antony-the-great.jpg
Apostle Alphaeus of the Seventy (05-26).jpg
Apostle Ananias of the Seventy (10-01).jpg
Apostle and Evangelist John the Theologian (05-08).jpg
Apostle and Evangelist Luke (10-18).jpg
Apostle and Evangelist Luke of the Seventy (04-22).jpg
Apostle and Evangelist Mark (04-25).jpg
Apostle and Evangelist Matthew (11-16).jpg
Apostle Andrew, the Holy and All-Praised First-Called (11-30).jpg
Apostle Andronicus of the Seventy and his fellow-laborer, Junia (05-17).jpg
Apostle Aquila of the Seventy (07-14).jpg
Apostle Aristarchus of the Seventy (04-15).jpg
Apostle Aristarchus of the Seventy (09-27).jpg
Apostle Aristobulus of the Seventy (10-31).jpg
Apostle Aristobulus of the Seventy, Bishop of Britain (03-16).jpg
Apostle Barnabas of the Seventy (06-11).jpg
Apostle Bartholomew of the Twelve (06-11).jpg
Apostle Carpus of the Seventy (05-26).jpg
Apostle Epίmakhos of Alexandria (10-31).jpg
Apostle Evodius (Euodias) of the Seventy (09-07).jpg
Apostle Hermas of the Seventy (05-31).jpg
Apostle Hermes of the Seventy (03-08).jpg
Apostle Herodion of the Seventy, and those with Him (04-08).jpg
Apostle James the Brother of Saint John the Theologian (04-30).jpg
Apostle James, son of Alphaeus (10-09).jpg
Apostle James, the Brother of the Lord (10-23).jpg
Apostle Jude the Brother of the Lord (06-19).jpg
Apostle Mark of the Seventy (09-27).jpg
Apostle Matthias of the Seventy (08-09).jpg
Apostle Nathaniel of the Seventy (04-22).jpg
Apostle Nicanor the Deacon of the Seventy (12-28).jpg
Apostle Onesimus of the Seventy (02-15).jpg
Apostle Philip of the Seventy, One of the Seven Deacons (10-11).jpg
Apostle Pudens of the Seventy (04-15).jpg
Apostle Quadratus of the Seventy (09-21).jpg
Apostle Silas of the Seventy (07-30).jpg
Apostle Silvanus of the Seventy (07-30).jpg
Apostle Simon the Zealot (05-10).jpg
Apostle Tertius of the Seventy (10-30).jpg
Apostle Thaddeus of the Seventy (08-21).jpg
Apostle Timothy of the Seventy (01-22).jpg
Apostle Titus of the Seventy and Bishop of Crete (08-25).jpg
Apostle Trophimus of the Seventy (04-15).jpg
Apostle Zacchaeus (04-20).jpg
Apostles Jason and Sosipater of the Seventy, the Virgin Kerkyra, and those with them (04-28).jpg
Apostles of the Seventy Archippus and Philemon, and Martyr Apphia (02-19).jpg
Apostles of the Seventy Philemon and Archippus, Martyr Apphia, wife of Philemon and Equal-to-the-Apostles, and Onesimus, disciple of Saint Paul (11-22).jpg
Apostles Patrobus, Hermes, Linus, Gaius, and Philologus, of the Seventy (11-05).jpg
Appearance of Christ to Saint Martin of Tours (02-13).jpg
Appearance of the Icon of the Mother of God “The Footprint” at Pochaev (04-17).jpg
Appearance of the Ivḗron Icon of the Mother of God (03-31).jpg
Appearance of the Mother of God to Saint Sergius of Radonezh (08-24).jpg
Appearance of the Smolensk “Directress” Icon of the Mother of God brought from Constantinople (07-28).jpg
Appearance of the Tikhvin Icon of the Mother of God (06-26).jpg
Arrival of the Ivḗron Icon of the Mother of God in Georgia (09-26).jpg
athanasius-the-great.jpg
bartholomew-apostle.jpg
basil-the-great.webp
Beginning of Great Lent (02-23).jpg
Beheading of Venerable Cornelius, Abbot of the Pskov Caves (02-20).jpg
Belynich Icon of the Mother of God (04-12).jpg
Blessed Andrew the Fool-For-Christ at Constantinople (10-02).jpg
Blessed Augustine, Bishop of Hippo (06-15).jpg
Blessed Basil of Moscow the Fool-For-Christ (08-02).jpg
Blessed Child Musa of Rome (05-16).jpg
Blessed Christopher, called Christesia (05-11).jpg
Blessed David IV, King of Georgia (01-26).jpg
Blessed Dovmont (Timothy), Prince of Pskov (05-20).jpg
Blessed Elesbaan, King of Ethiopia (10-24).jpg
Blessed Gregory, Patriarch of Antioch (04-20).jpg
Blessed James of Borovichi, Wonderworker of Novgorod (05-22).jpg
Blessed John of Moscow the Fool-For-Christ (07-03).jpg
Blessed John “the Hairy” and Fool-For-Christ at Rostov (09-03).jpg
Blessed John “the Hairy” and Fool-For-Christ at Rostov (11-12).jpg
Blessed Laurence the Fool-For-Christ at Kaluga (08-10).jpg
Blessed Nicholas (Salos) of Pskov the Fool-For-Christ (02-28).jpg
Blessed Nikḗtas the Hidden of Constantinople (09-09).jpg
Blessed Peter, King of Bulgaria (01-30).jpg
Blessed Prince Gleb Andreevich, son of Saint Andrew Bogoliubsky (06-20).jpg
Blessed Stephen, King of Serbia (07-19).jpg
Blessed Thais of Egypt (05-10).jpg
Blessed Xenia of St. Petersburg (01-24).jpg
Blessed Yaropolk (in Baptism Peter), Prince of Vladimir-Volhynia (11-22).jpg
Bright Monday (04-13).jpg
Bright Saturday (04-18).jpg
Bright Thursday (04-16).jpg
Bright Tuesday (04-14).jpg
Bright Wednesday (04-15).jpg
Burial of Saint Andrew the Prince (07-04).jpg
Childmartyr Gabriel of Bialystok (04-20).jpg
Church New Year (09-01).jpg
Commemoration of the Apparition of the Sign of the Precious Cross Over Jerusalem, in 351 AD (05-07).jpg
Commemoration of the Earthquake of 447 (09-25).jpg
Commemoration of the Founding of Constantinople (05-11).jpg
Commemoration of the Founding of the Church of the Resurrection (Holy Sepulchre) at Jerusalem (09-13).jpg
Commemoration of the Holy Fathers of the Second Ecumenical Council (05-22).jpg
Commemoration of the Holy Fathers of the Seventh Ecumenical Council (10-11).jpg
Commemoration of the Holy Fathers of the Sixth Ecumenical Council (01-23).jpg
Commemoration of the Holy Righteous David the King, Joseph the Betrothed, and James the Brother of the Lord (12-27).jpg
Commemoration of the Kazan Icon of the Mother of God and the deliverance from the Poles (10-22).jpg
Commemoration of the Miracle of the Archangel Michael at Colossae (09-06).jpg
Commemoration of the Shepherds in Bethlehem who were watching their flocks, and went to see the Lord (12-25).jpg
Commemoration of the Vladimir Icon of the Mother of God and the deliverance of Moscow from the Invasion of Tamerlane (08-26).jpg
Commemoration of the Weeping Icon of the Mother of God “of the Sign” at Novgorod (11-27).jpg
Conception of the Honorable Glorious Prophet, Forerunner and Baptist John (09-23).jpg
Conception of the Most Holy Theotokos by Saint Anna (12-09).jpg
Confessors Barses and Eulogius, Bishops of Edessa, and Protogenes, Bishop of Carrhae (08-25).jpg
Consecration of the Church of the Holy Great Martyr George in Lydda (11-03).jpg
constantine-and-helen.jpg
crucifixion.jpg
cyril-and-methodius.jpg
david-prophet-king.jpg
Day of Rejoicing (04-21).jpg
Discovery of the Relics of the Holy Great Martyr Ephraim (01-03).jpg
Don Icon of the Mother of God (08-19).jpg
Dormition of the Righteous Anna, the Mother of the Most Holy Theotokos (07-25).jpg
elijah-prophet.jpg
elisha-prophet.jpg
Empress Augusta, Porphyrius the General, the 50 philosophers and the 200 Soldiers martyred with the Great Martyr Katherine (11-24).jpg
Entrance of Saint Nino (Nina) the Enlightener into Georgia (05-19).jpg
Entrance of the Apostle Andrew into Georgia (11-30).jpg
Entry of Our Lord into Jerusalem (Palm Sunday) (04-05).jpg
ephrem-the-syrian.jpg
Equal of the Apostles and Emperor Constantine with his Mother Helen (05-21).jpg
Equal-to-the-Apostles Blessed Great Princess Olga (in Holy Baptism Helen) (07-11).jpg
Equals of the Apostles and Teachers of the Slavs, Cyril and Methodius (05-11).jpg
Equals of the Apostles, Emperor Mirian and Empress Nana of Georgia; Saint Sidonia; the Commemoration of the apparition of the Pillar with the Robe of  (10-01).jpg
Eve of the Nativity of our Lord (12-24).jpg
Eve of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-05).jpg
Fathers of the First Six Councils (07-19).jpg
Feast of All Saints of Georgia (06-26).jpg
Feast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-06).jpg
filelist.txt
Finding of the relics of Saint Basil, Bishop of Ryazan (06-10).jpg
Finding of the Relics of Saint Hilarion, Archbishop of Verey (07-11).jpg
Finding of the relics of Saint Theodore, Prince of Smolensk and Yaroslavl, and his children (03-05).jpg
Finding of the Relics of Saints Basil and Constantine, Princes of Yaroslavl (06-08).jpg
Finding of the relics of Venerable Ambrose of Optina (06-27).jpg
Finding of the relics of Venerable Cyril, Abbot of Novoezersk, Vologda (11-07).jpg
Finding of the relics of Venerable Maximus the Greek (July 4, 1996) (07-04).jpg
First and second finding of the Honorable Head of the Holy Glorious Prophet, Forerunner, and Baptist of the Lord, John (02-24).jpg
First finding of the relics of Saint Metrophanes, first Bishop of Voronezh (08-07).jpg
First opening of the relics of Saint Tikhon of Zadonsk (05-14).jpg
First Translation of the relics of Saint Herman, Archbishop of Kazan (09-25).jpg
Five Nuns beheaded in Persia Martyrs Thecla, Mariamne, Martha, Mary, and Ennatha (06-09).jpg
Forefeast of the Annunciation (03-24).jpg
Forefeast of the Dormition of the Mother of God (08-14).jpg
Forefeast of the Entry into the Temple of the Most Holy Theotokos (11-20).jpg
Forefeast of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-01).jpg
Forefeast of the Nativity of our Lord (12-20).jpg
Forefeast of the Nativity of our Lord (12-21).jpg
Forefeast of the Nativity of our Lord (12-22).jpg
Forefeast of the Nativity of our Lord (12-23).jpg
Forefeast of the Nativity of the Mother of God (09-07).jpg
Forefeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-02).jpg
Forefeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-03).jpg
Forefeast of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-04).jpg
Forefeast of the Transfiguration of our Lord (08-05).jpg
george-of-lydda.jpg
Glorification of Saint Innocent, Metropolitan of Moscow, Enlightener of the Aleuts, Apostle to the Americas (10-06).jpg
Glorification of Saint John of Kronstadt (06-14).jpg
Glorification of Saint Tikhon, Patriarch of Moscow and All Russia, Enlightener of North America (10-09).jpg
Glorification of the Priestmartyr Alexander Hotovitzky (12-04).jpg
Glorification of Venerable Herman of Alaska, Wonderworker of All America (08-09).jpg
Glorification of Venerable Zabulon and Sosanna, parents of Saint Nino, Enlightener of Georgia (05-20).jpg
Grand Duchess Elizabeth (07-18).jpg
Great and Holy Friday (04-10).jpg
Great and Holy Saturday (04-11).jpg
Great and Holy Thursday (04-09).jpg
Great and Holy Tuesday (04-07).jpg
Great and Holy Wednesday (04-08).jpg
Great Martyr Anastasia the Deliverer from Poisons, her teacher, Martyr Chrysogonos, and many with them (12-22).jpg
Great Martyr Euphemia the All-praised (09-16).jpg
Great Martyr Irene (05-05).jpg
Great Martyr Katherine of Alexandria (11-24).jpg
Great Martyr Marina (Margaret) of Antioch (07-17).jpg
Great Martyr Mercurius of Caesarea, in Cappadocia (11-24).jpg
Great Martyr Theodore the Tyro (Recruit) (02-17).jpg
Greatmartyr and Healer Panteleimon (07-27).jpg
Greatmartyr Artemius at Antioch (10-20).jpg
Greatmartyr Barbara and Martyr Juliana, at Heliopolis in Syria (12-04).jpg
Greatmartyr Euphemia the All-praised (07-11).jpg
Greatmartyr Eustáthios Placidas, with his wife and children, of Rome (09-20).jpg
Greatmartyr James the Persian (11-27).jpg
Greatmartyr Ketevan, Queen of Georgia (09-13).jpg
Greatmartyr Niketas the Goth (09-15).jpg
Greatmartyr Paraskevi of Iconium (10-28).jpg
Greatmartyr Prince Bidzini and Martyrs Princes Elizabar and Shalvi, of Georgia (09-18).jpg
Greatmartyr Procopius of Caesarea, in Palestine (07-08).jpg
Greatmartyr Theodore Stratelates “the General” (02-08).jpg
Greatmartyr, Victory-bearer, and Wonderworker George (04-23).jpg
gregory-palamas.jpg
gregory-theologian.jpeg
Hierarch Peter, first Catholicos of Georgia (11-30).jpg
Hierarch Samuel, Second Catholicos of Georgia (11-30).jpg
Hieromartyr Abibus, Bishop of Nekresi in Georgia (11-29).jpg
Hieromartyr Abramius, Bishop of Arbela in Assyria (02-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Alexander, Bishop of Adrianopolis, and the Martyrs Heraclius, Anna, Elizabeth, Theodota, and Glyceria (10-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Alexander, Bishop of Comana (08-12).jpg
Hieromartyr and Metropolitan of Moscow and Krutitsy, Peter Polyansky (10-10).jpg
Hieromartyr Antherus (Antheros) Pope of Rome (08-05).jpg
Hieromartyr Anthimus, Bishop of Nicomedia and those with him (09-03).jpg
Hieromartyr Antipas, Bishop of Pergamum and Disciple of Saint John the Theologian (04-11).jpg
Hieromartyr Aristion, Bishop of Alexandria (09-03).jpg
Hieromartyr Artemon of Laodikeia (04-13).jpg
Hieromartyr Athanasios, Venerable Anthousa, and others (08-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Athenogenes, Bishop of Heracleopolis, and his ten disciples (07-16).jpg
Hieromartyr Autonomus, Bishop in Italy (09-12).jpg
Hieromartyr Babylas, Bishop of Antioch, and those with him (09-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Basil of Ancyra (03-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Basil, Bishop of Amasea (04-26).jpg
Hieromartyr Benjamin, Metropolitan of Petrograd and Gdovsk, and those with him (07-31).jpg
Hieromartyr Blaise, Bishop of Sebaste (02-11).jpg
Hieromartyr Clement, Bishop of Ancyra, and Martyr Agathangelus (01-23).jpg
Hieromartyr Clement, Pope of Rome (11-25).jpg
Hieromartyr Cornelius the Centurion (09-13).jpg
Hieromartyr Cyprian, Bishop of Carthage (08-31).jpg
Hieromartyr Cyprian, Virgin Martyr Justina, and Martyr Theoctistus, of Nicomedia (10-02).jpg
Hieromartyr Cyril, Bishop of Gortyna in Crete (07-09).jpg
Hieromartyr Desan, Bishop in Persia, and 272 others with him (04-09).jpg
Hieromartyr Dionysius the Areopagite, Bishop of Athens (10-03).jpg
Hieromartyr Dionysius, Bishop of Alexandria (10-05).jpg
Hieromartyr Dorotheus, Bishop of Tyre (06-05).jpg
Hieromartyr Dositheus of Tbilisi (09-12).jpg
Hieromartyr Eleutherius, Bishop of Illyria, his mother, Martyr Evanthia, and Caribus the Eparch (12-15).jpg
Hieromartyr Eusebius, Bishop of Samosata (06-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Eutyches, disciple of Saint John the Theologian (08-24).jpg
Hieromartyr Gabriel the Lesser (03-17).jpg
Hieromartyr Gregory (Peradze) of Georgia (11-23).jpg
Hieromartyr Gregory, Bishop of Greater Armenia, Equal of the Apostles, Enlightener of Armenia (09-30).jpg
Hieromartyr Haralambos, Bishop of Magnesia in Thessaly, the Martyrs Porphyrius and Baptus, and three women Martyrs (02-10).jpg
Hieromartyr Helladius, Bishop in the East (05-28).jpg
Hieromartyr Hermogenes, Patriarch of Moscow and All Russia (05-12).jpg
Hieromartyr Hermogenes, Patriarch of Moscow, Wonderworker of All Russia (02-17).jpg
Hieromartyr Hermolaus and Martyrs Hermippus and Hermocrates at Nicomedia (07-26).jpg
Hieromartyr Hierotheus, Bishop of Athens (10-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Hippolytus, and those with him (01-30).jpg
Hieromartyr Ignatius the God-Bearer, Bishop of Antioch (12-20).jpg
Hieromartyr Irenaeus, Bishop of Lyons (08-23).jpg
Hieromartyr Isidore and 72 others at Yuriev, Estonia (01-08).jpg
Hieromartyr Januarius, Bishop of Benevento, and his companions, at Pozzuoli (04-21).jpg
Hieromartyr Joannicius of Serbia (06-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Kirion II, Catholicos-Patriarch of All Georgia (03-12).jpg
Hieromartyr Kirion II, Catholicos-Patriarch of All Georgia (06-27).jpg
Hieromartyr Kozman (07-18).jpg
Hieromartyr Kuksha and Venerable Pimen of the Kiev Near Caves (08-27).jpg
Hieromartyr Lucian the Presbyter of the Kiev Caves (10-15).jpg
Hieromartyr Macarius, Archimandrite of Kanev and Pereyaslavl (09-07).jpg
Hieromartyr Marcellus, Bishop of Apamea (08-14).jpg
Hieromartyr Mark, Bishop of Arethusa, who suffered under Julian the Apostate (03-29).jpg
Hieromartyr Maxim Sandovich (09-06).jpg
Hieromartyr Methodius, Bishop of Patara (06-20).jpg
Hieromartyr Metrophanes (Chang Tzi-tzung), first Chinese priest and the martyrs of the Boxer Rising in China (06-11).jpg
Hieromartyr Metropolitan Seraphim (Chichagov) (11-28).jpg
Hieromartyr Mocius the Presbyter of Amphipolis in Macedonia (05-11).jpg
Hieromartyr Mίlos (or Milēs) the Wonderworker, and two disciples (11-10).jpg
Hieromartyr Nestor, Bishop of Magydos in Pamphylia (02-28).jpg
Hieromartyr Nikḗtas of Remesiana (06-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Pancratius, Bishop of Taormina in Sicily (07-09).jpg
Hieromartyr Paphnutius of Jerusalem (04-19).jpg
Hieromartyr Patrick, Bishop of Prusa, and his companions (05-19).jpg
Hieromartyr Peter, Archbishop of Alexandria (11-25).jpg
Hieromartyr Peter, Metropolitan of Serbia (09-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Philip, Bishop of Heraclea and with him the Martyrs Severus, Memnon, and 37 Soldiers in Thrace (08-20).jpg
Hieromartyr Philip, Metropolitan of Moscow and All Russia (01-09).jpg
Hieromartyr Philosophos of St. Petersburg (05-31).jpg
Hieromartyr Platon the Newmartyr of Banjaluka (04-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Polycarp, Bishop of Smyrna (02-23).jpg
Hieromartyr Proterius, Patriarch of Alexandria (02-28).jpg
Hieromartyr Savva (Trlajic) of Serbia (04-22).jpg
Hieromartyr Seraphim (Samoilovich), Archbishop of Uglich (11-04).jpg
Hieromartyr Simeon, Bishop in Persia, and those with him (04-17).jpg
Hieromartyr Simeon, kinsman of the Lord, second Bishop of Jerusalem (04-27).jpg
Hieromartyr Stephen, Pope of Rome, and those with him (08-02).jpg
Hieromartyr Terence, Bishop of Iconium (06-21).jpg
Hieromartyr Theodore (Tevdore) of Kvelta (06-08).jpg
Hieromartyr Theodore of Atchara (02-17).jpg
Hieromartyr Theodore of Perge in Pamphylia, his mother, Philippa, and Martyrs Dioscorus, Socrates, and Dionysius (04-21).jpg
Hieromartyr Theodotus, Bishop of Ancyra (06-07).jpg
Hieromartyr Theodotus, Bishop of Cyrenia (03-02).jpg
Hieromartyr Theopemptus, Bishop of Nicomedia, and Martyr Theonas (01-05).jpg
Hieromartyr Therapon, Bishop of Cyprus (05-25).jpg
Hieromartyr Therapontus of Cyprus (05-14).jpg
Hieromartyr Timothy, Bishop of Prusa (06-10).jpg
Hieromartyr Vitalius, Bishop of Ravenna (07-23).jpg
Hieromartyr Zeno, Bishop of Verona (04-12).jpg
Hieromartyr Zenobios and his sister Zenobia, of Aegæ in Cilicia (10-30).jpg
Hieromartyrs Akepsimas, Bishop in Persia, Presbyter Joseph, and Deacon Aeithalas (11-03).jpg
Hieromartyrs John the Bishop and Jacob (James) the Presbyter, of Persia (11-01).jpg
Hieromartyrs Marcellus, Bishop of Sicily, Philagrius, Bishop of Cyprus, and Pancratius, Bishop of Taoromina (02-09).jpg
Hodegetria Icon of the Mother of God (Παναγία Οδηγήτρια) (06-20).jpg
Holy and Righteous Ancestors of God, Joachim and Anna (09-09).jpg
Holy Apostles of the Seventy and Deacons Prochorus, Nicanor, Timon, and Parmenas (07-28).jpg
Holy Empress Irene (Schema-nun Xenia) (08-13).jpg
Holy Fathers of the Shio-Mgvime Monastery (01-04).jpg
Holy Forty Women Martyrs and Martyr Ammon the Deacon, their teacher, at Heraclea in Thrace (09-01).jpg
Holy Great Prince Vladimir (Basil in Baptism), Equal of the Apostles, and Enlightener of Rus' (07-15).jpg
Holy King Stephen of Serbia (09-24).jpg
Holy Martyr and Confessor Michael and his councilor, Theodore, Wonderworkers of Chernigov (09-20).jpg
Holy Martyrs and Confessors Gurias, Samonas, and Habibus, of Edessa (11-15).jpg
Holy Monastic Fathers slain at Sinai and Raithu (01-14).jpg
Holy New Martyr Ignatius (Bazyluk) (08-09).jpg
HOLY PASCHA The Resurrection of Our Lord (04-12).jpg
Holy Pentecost (05-31).jpg
Holy Prophet and God-seer Moses (09-04).jpg
Holy Prophet Malachi (01-03).jpg
Holy Prophet Zachariah and Righteous Elizabeth, parents of Saint John the Baptist (09-05).jpg
Holy Queen Dinar (06-30).jpg
Holy Right-believing Princess Militsa of Serbia (07-19).jpg
Holy Righteous David the King (12-27).jpg
Holy Righteous Joseph the Betrothed (12-27).jpg
Holy Unmercenary Physician Diomedes (08-16).jpg
Holy Virgin Martyr Theodosίa of Tyre (04-03).jpg
Holy Virgin Martyr Theodosίa of Tyre (05-29).jpg
Holy Woman Olympias (Olympiada) the Deaconess of Constantinople (07-25).jpg
Holy Wonderworkers and Unmercenaries Cosmas and Damian of Mesopotamia (11-01).jpg
Holy Wonderworkers and Unmercenaries Cyrus and John, and those with them (01-31).jpg
Holy Wonderworking Unmercenary Physicians Cosmas and Damian at Rome (07-01).jpg
Holy, All-Praised Apostle Philip (11-14).jpg
Holy, Glorious Apostle Thomas (10-06).jpg
Holy, Glorious Demetrios the Myrrh-gusher of Thessaloniki (10-26).jpg
Holy, Glorious Prophet Elijah (07-20).jpg
Holy, Righteous Anna the Prophetess (02-03).jpg
Holy, Righteous Simeon the God-Receiver (02-03).jpg
Icon of Sophia, the Wisdom of God (09-08).jpg
Icon of Sophia, the Wisdom of God (Novgorod) (08-15).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Akhtyr (07-02).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Andronicus (10-22).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Balikin (06-30).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Chirsk-Pskov (07-16).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Cyprus (02-19).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Cyprus (05-22).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Filersk (10-20).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Galatea (07-04).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Georgia (08-22).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Gerbovets (10-01).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Greben (07-28).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Igor (06-05).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Kaluga (09-02).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Kasperov (04-05).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Kiev-Bratsk (06-02).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Kiev-Bratsk (09-06).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Koloch (07-09).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Konevits (07-10).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Korsun (10-09).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Lesna (09-14).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Lubyatov (03-19).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Lydda or “the Roman” (06-26).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Minsk (08-13).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Mount Athos, “Sweet Kissing” (03-27).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Nicea (05-28).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Novonikḗta (09-15).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Pochaev (07-23).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Pochaev (09-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Rudens (10-12).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Rzhevsk (07-11).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Saint Theodore (03-14).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Saint Theodore (08-16).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Shui (07-28).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Tambov (07-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of the Kiev Caves (08-17).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Tolga (07-18).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Tolga (08-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Volokolamsk (03-03).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of White Lake (06-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of White Lake (07-28).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Yakhrom (10-14).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Yaroslavl (06-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God of Zhirovits (05-07).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God the “Milk-Giver” of the Hilandar Monastery on Mount Athos (07-03).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God the “Milkgiver” (01-12).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God the “Rescuer of the Drowning” (12-20).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “Areovindus” (02-10).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “Comfort” or “Consolation” (01-21).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “Elets-Chernigov” (02-05).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Akathist” (03-27).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Akathist” of Zographou Monastery (10-10).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Myrtle Tree” (09-24).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Passion” (05-17).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Passion” (08-13).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “of the Sign”, the “Kursk-Root” (09-08).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God “Of the Three Hands” (06-28).jpg
Icon of the Mother of God, “Albazin” or “The Word was made Flesh” (03-09).jpg
ignatius-of-antioch.jpg
Igoumen Parthenios of Kiziltash Monastery (09-04).jpg
Inexhastible Chalice Icon of the Mother of God (05-05).jpg
innocent-of-alaska.jpg
Ivḗron Icon of the Mother of God (02-12).jpg
james-zebedee.jpg
john-chrysostom.jpg
john-climacus.jpg
john-evangelist.jpg
john-the-baptist.jpg
jude-apostle.jpg
Kazan Icons of the Mother of God in Kazan, St. Petersburg, and Moscow (07-08).jpg
Kursk Root Icon of the Mother of God “of the Sign” (03-08).jpg
Leavetaking of Pascha (05-20).jpg
Leavetaking of the Annunciation (03-26).jpg
Leavetaking of the Meeting of our Lord in the Temple (02-09).jpg
Leavetaking of the Nativity of the Mother of God (09-12).jpg
Leavetaking of the Theophany of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-14).jpg
luke-apostle.jpg
luke-of-crimea.jpg
Machairotissa Icon of the Mother of God (10-18).jpg
macrina-the-elder.jpg
mark-evangelist.jpg
Martyr Abo the Perfumer, of Tbilisi, Georgia (01-08).jpg
Martyr Abraham of Bulgaria (04-01).jpg
Martyr Acacius of Apamea (07-28).jpg
Martyr Agatha of Palermo in Sicily (02-05).jpg
Martyr Agathocleia (09-17).jpg
Martyr Agathonicus of Nicomedia, and those with him, who suffered under Maximian (08-22).jpg
Martyr Agrippina of Rome (06-23).jpg
Martyr Aithalas of Persia (09-01).jpg
Martyr Alexander and Virgin Martyr Antonina at Constantinople (06-10).jpg
Martyr Alexandra the Empress, wife of Diocletian (04-23).jpg
Martyr Ananias of Persia (12-01).jpg
Martyr and Archdeacon Euplus of Catania (08-11).jpg
Martyr and Archdeacon Laurence, and those with him, of Rome (08-10).jpg
Martyr Andrew Stratelates, and 2,593 soldiers with him, in Cilicia (08-19).jpg
Martyr Antonina of Nicea (06-13).jpg
Martyr Antonina of Nicea, in Bithynia (03-01).jpg
Martyr Apollonius of Sardis (07-10).jpg
Martyr Aquilina of Byblos in Syria (06-13).jpg
Martyr Archil II, King of Georgia (06-21).jpg
Martyr Arethas and 4,299 Martyrs with him (10-24).jpg
Martyr Ariádnē of Phrygia (09-18).jpg
Martyr Ashot Curapalati, King of Artanuji (01-29).jpg
Martyr Avakum the Deacon of Serbia (12-17).jpg
Martyr Barlaam of Caesarea, in Cappadocia (11-19).jpg
Martyr Barypsabas in Dalmatia (09-10).jpg
Martyr Basilissa of Nicomedia (09-03).jpg
Martyr Bassa of Edessa and her sons Theogonius, Agapius, and Pistus (08-21).jpg
Martyr Blaise of Caesarea, in Cappadocia (02-03).jpg
Martyr Boniface at Tarsus in Cilicia, and Righteous Aglaϊa of Rome (12-19).jpg
Martyr Callinicus of Gangra in Asia Minor (07-29).jpg
Martyr Callistratus and 49 companions (09-27).jpg
Martyr Charitina of Amisos (10-05).jpg
Martyr Chariton (09-09).jpg
Martyr Christina of Tyre (07-24).jpg
Martyr Christopher of Guria, Georgia (08-16).jpg
Martyr Christopher of Lycia, and, with him, the Martyrs Callinika and Aquilina (05-09).jpg
Martyr Christos of Preveza (08-05).jpg
Martyr Chronides of Alexandria and those with him (09-13).jpg
Martyr Conon of Isauria (03-05).jpg
Martyr Conon the Gardener of Pamphylia (03-05).jpg
Martyr Constantine, King of Georgia (11-10).jpg
Martyr Crescens of Myra in Lycia (04-13).jpg
Martyr Cyril the Deacon of Heliopolis, and those with him, who suffered under Julian the Apostate (03-29).jpg
Martyr Dometius of Persia and his two disciples (08-07).jpg
Martyr Doulas of Cilicia (06-15).jpg
Martyr Eleutherius of Constantinople (08-04).jpg
Martyr Emilian of Silistria in Bulgaria (07-18).jpg
Martyr Epicharis of Rome (09-27).jpg
Martyr Eudokia of Heliopolis (03-01).jpg
Martyr Eudokia of Persia (08-04).jpg
Martyr Eupsychius of Caesarea, in Cappadocia (04-09).jpg
Martyr Eusignius of Antioch (08-05).jpg
Martyr Eustathius of Mtskheta in Georgia (07-29).jpg
Martyr Evdemoz, Catholicos of Georgia (10-04).jpg
Martyr Felicitas of Rome, and her seven sons (01-25).jpg
Martyr Gelasius (06-06).jpg
Martyr Gerontius, and those with him, of Saint David Gareji Monastery, Georgia (08-12).jpg
Martyr Gobron (Michael) and 133 soldiers, of Georgia (11-17).jpg
Martyr Gorazd of Prague, Bohemia and Moravo-Cilezsk (09-04).jpg
Martyr Gordius at Caesarea, in Cappadocia (01-03).jpg
Martyr Hermias at Comana (05-31).jpg
Martyr Hermione, daughter of Saint Philip the Deacon (09-04).jpg
Martyr Hippolytus of Rome and those with him Martyr Concordia, Irenaeus, and Abundius (08-13).jpg
Martyr Hyacinth of Caesarea, in Cappadocia, and those with him (07-03).jpg
Martyr Hypomone (04-05).jpg
Martyr Ilia Chavchavadze of Georgia (07-20).jpg
Martyr Irenarchus and Seven Women Martyrs at Sebaste (11-28).jpg
Martyr John of Kazan (01-24).jpg
Martyr John of Vlachia, Romania (05-12).jpg
Martyr John the Soldier at Constantinople (07-30).jpg
Martyr John, Abbot of the Zedazeni Monastery (12-12).jpg
Martyr Julian of Constantinople and those with him (08-09).jpg
Martyr Julian of Emesa (02-06).jpg
Martyr Julian of Tarsus, in Cilicia (06-21).jpg
Martyr Justin the Philosopher and those with him at Rome (06-01).jpg
Martyr Justus at Rome (07-14).jpg
Martyr Juvenal of Alaska (09-24).jpg
Martyr Kozman (10-17).jpg
Martyr Kyriake of Nicomedia (07-07).jpg
Martyr Longinus the Centurion, who stood at the Cross of the Lord (10-16).jpg
Martyr Luarsab II, King of Georgia (06-21).jpg
Martyr Lucian the Presbyter of Antioch (10-15).jpg
Martyr Ludmilla the grandmother of Saint Wenceslaus, Prince of the Czechs (09-16).jpg
Martyr Lupus (10-26).jpg
Martyr Lupus, slave of Saint Demetrius of Thessalonica (08-23).jpg
Martyr Mamas of Caesarea in Cappadocia (09-02).jpg
Martyr Marinus (03-17).jpg
Martyr Marinus of Rome (12-16).jpg
Martyr Marinus the Soldier at Caesarea in Palestine (08-07).jpg
Martyr Markella of Chios (07-22).jpg
Martyr Matrona of Thessalonica (03-27).jpg
Martyr Maximus of Ephesus (04-30).jpg
Martyr Melitinḗ of Marcianopolis (09-16).jpg
Martyr Memelchtha of Persia (10-05).jpg
Martyr Menas of Egypt (11-11).jpg
Martyr Mercurius of Smolensk (11-24).jpg
Martyr Michael, Abbot in Armenia, and 36 Fathers with him (10-01).jpg
Martyr Michael, Prince of Tver (11-22).jpg
Martyr Moses (Macinic) the Confessor (10-21).jpg
Martyr Myron the Presbyter of Cyzicus (08-17).jpg
Martyr Myrope of Chios (12-02).jpg
Martyr Nectan of Hartland (06-17).jpg
Martyr Neophytus of Nicea (01-21).jpg
Martyr Neophytus of Urbin, Georgia (10-28).jpg
Martyr Nestor of Thessalonica (10-27).jpg
Martyr Nicholas (Nikoloz) Dvali in Jerusalem (02-12).jpg
Martyr Nikephoros of Antioch, in Syria (02-09).jpg
Martyr Nikon and 199 disciples with him in Sicily (03-23).jpg
Martyr Paramon and 370 Martyrs in Bithynia (11-29).jpg
Martyr Paraskevi of Rome (07-26).jpg
Martyr Pausilippus of Heraclea in Thrace (04-08).jpg
Martyr Pelagia of Tarsus (10-07).jpg
Martyr Peter the Aleut (09-24).jpg
Martyr Philetus the Senator, his wife and sons, and those with them in Illyria (03-23).jpg
Martyr Philosophus at Alexandria (05-31).jpg
Martyr Philothea the Monastic (02-19).jpg
Martyr Philoumenus of Ancyra (11-29).jpg
Martyr Phokas the Gardener of Sinope (09-22).jpg
Martyr Photini the Samaritan Woman, her sons, and those with them (03-20).jpg
Martyr Platon of Ancyra (11-18).jpg
Martyr Polycarp of Alexandria (04-02).jpg
Martyr Polydorus of Cyprus (09-03).jpg
Martyr Polyeuktos of Melitene in Armenia (01-09).jpg
Martyr Porphyrius the Actor (09-15).jpg
Martyr Quadratus and those with him at Corinth (03-10).jpg
Martyr Quadratus and those with him at Nicomedia (03-10).jpg
Martyr Razhden of Persia the Georgian (08-03).jpg
Martyr Romanus the Deacon of Caesarea (11-18).jpg
Martyr Sabinus of Egypt (03-16).jpg
Martyr Salome the Georgian (07-20).jpg
Martyr Savva Stratelates “the General” of Rome, and 70 soldiers with him (04-24).jpg
Martyr Sebastian at Rome, and his companions (12-18).jpg
Martyr Severian of Sebaste (09-09).jpg
Martyr Solomonia, mother of the Holy Seven Maccabee Martyrs (08-01).jpg
Martyr Sophia and her three daughters at Rome (09-17).jpg
Martyr Sozon of Cilicia (09-07).jpg
Martyr Suchias and his Soldiers in Georgia (04-15).jpg
Martyr Susanna, Queen of Georgia (08-28).jpg
Martyr Tatiana of Rome, and those who suffered with her (01-12).jpg
Martyr Tation (Tatio) of Claudiopolis (08-24).jpg
Martyr Terence and 40 others beheaded at Carthage (04-10).jpg
Martyr Themistocles of Myra in Lycia (12-21).jpg
Martyr Theodota and her three sons in Bithynia (07-29).jpg
Martyr Theodotus of Ancyra, and with him the seven Virgin Martyrs Alexandra, Tecusa, Claudia, Phaine, Euphraisa, Matrona, and Julia, who suffered unde (05-18).jpg
Martyr Thomais of Alexandria (04-13).jpg
Martyr Timothy the Reader and his wife, Maura, in Egypt (05-03).jpg
Martyr Tryphaίnē at Cyzicus (01-31).jpg
Martyr Tryphon of Lampsacus Near Apamea in Syria (02-01).jpg
Martyr Varus, and seven Monastic Martyrs with him (10-19).jpg
Martyr Victor at Damascus (11-11).jpg
Martyr Victor, and his companions, of Nicomedia (04-18).jpg
Martyr Vincent of Spain (11-11).jpg
Martyr Wenceslaus, Prince of the Czechs (09-28).jpg
Martyr Zosimus the Soldier at Antioch, in Pisidia (06-19).jpg
Martyr Zēnaίda (Zenais) of Caesarea in Palestine (06-07).jpg
Martyrdom of the Great-martyr George of Georgia (11-10).jpg
Martyred Fathers and Mothers of Atchara (05-29).jpg
Martyred Holy Fathers who were slain at the Monastery of Saint Savva (03-20).jpg
Martyrs Abercius and Helen, children of the Apostle Alphæus (05-26).jpg
Martyrs Acindynus, Pegasius, Aphthonius, Elpidephorus, Anempodistus, and 7,000 with them, of Persia (11-02).jpg
Martyrs Adrian and Natalia and 23 companions, of Nicomedia (08-26).jpg
Martyrs Africanus, Publius, and Terence, of Carthage (03-13).jpg
Martyrs Agapius, Publius, Timolaus, Romulus, two named Dionysius, and two named Alexander, at Caesarea in Palestine (03-15).jpg
Martyrs Agathopodes the Deacon and Theodulus the Reader at Thessalonica (04-05).jpg
Martyrs Akepsimas and Aithalas of Egypt (12-11).jpg
Martyrs Amphianus and Edesius of Lycia (04-02).jpg
Martyrs Anatolius and Protoleon, soldiers converted by witnessing the martyrdom of Saint George (04-23).jpg
Martyrs and Passion-Bearers Boris and Gleb (07-24).jpg
Martyrs and Unmercenaries Cosmas and Damian in Cilicia, and their brothers, Leontius, Anthimus, and Eutropius (10-17).jpg
Martyrs Anicetus and Photius of Nicomedia, and those with them (08-12).jpg
Martyrs Anthony, John, and Eustathius of Vilnius (04-14).jpg
Martyrs Aristocles the Presbyter, Demetrian the Deacon, and Athanasius the Reader, of Cyprus (06-20).jpg
Martyrs Basil and Theodore of the Kiev Caves (08-11).jpg
Martyrs Basilissa and Anastasia of Rome, disciples of Apostles Peter and Paul (04-15).jpg
Martyrs Callista and her brothers, Evodius and Hermogenes, at Nicomedia (09-01).jpg
Martyrs Cantidius, Cantidian, and Sibelius (Sobel) of Egypt (08-05).jpg
Martyrs Carpus, Papylus, Agathadorus, and Agathonica, at Pergamum (10-13).jpg
Martyrs Christopher, Theonas, and Anthony, at Rome (04-19).jpg
Martyrs Chrysanthus and Daria, and those with them at Rome (03-19).jpg
Martyrs Dada, Maximus, and Quinctilian, at Dorostolum (04-28).jpg
Martyrs David and Constantine, Princes of Georgia (10-02).jpg
Martyrs David and Tarichan of Georgia (05-18).jpg
Martyrs Diodorus and Rhodopianus—Deacons, at Aphrodisia in Anatolia (04-29).jpg
Martyrs Eugene, Candidus, Valerian, and Aquila, at Trebizond (01-21).jpg
Martyrs Eulampius and Eulampia, at Nicomedia, and 200 Martyrs with them (10-10).jpg
Martyrs Eusebius, Neon, Leontius, Longinus, and others, at Nicomedia (04-24).jpg
Martyrs Eustratius, Auxentius, Eugene, Mardarius, and Orestes, at Sebaste (12-13).jpg
Martyrs Eutropius, Cleonicus, and Basiliscus of Amasea (03-03).jpg
Martyrs Florus and Laurus of Illyria (08-18).jpg
Martyrs Gaius, Dasius, and Zoticus at Nicomedia (10-21).jpg
Martyrs Galaction and his wife, Epistemis, at Emesa (11-05).jpg
Martyrs Gerontius and Basilides (04-01).jpg
Martyrs Gervasius, Nazarius, Protasius, and Celsus of Milan (10-14).jpg
Martyrs Hermylus and Stratonicus of Belgrade (01-13).jpg
Martyrs Innas, Pinnas, and Rimmas, disciples of the Apostle Andrew, in Scythia (01-20).jpg
Martyrs Isaac, Apollos, and Quadratus, of Nicomedia (04-21).jpg
Martyrs Isidore and Myrope of Chios (05-14).jpg
Martyrs James (Jacob) the Presbyter, and Azadanes and Abdicius, Deacons, of Persia (04-10).jpg
Martyrs Kalliniki and Basilissa (03-22).jpg
Martyrs killed by the Latins at the Ivḗron Monastery on Mount Athos (05-13).jpg
Martyrs Kyriaina and Juliana in Cilicia (11-01).jpg
Martyrs Kyriake, Kaleria, and Mary of Caesarea, in Palestine (06-07).jpg
Martyrs Leontius, Hypatius, and Theodulus at Tripoli in Syria (06-18).jpg
Martyrs Mark and Mocius (07-03).jpg
Martyrs Maurice and his son, Photinus, and Martyrs Theodore, Philip, and 70 soldiers, at Apamea in Syria (02-22).jpg
Martyrs Melasippus, Karina, their son, Antoninus, and forty children converted by their martyrdom, at Ancyra (11-07).jpg
Martyrs Menas, Hermogenes, and Eugraphus, of Alexandria (12-10).jpg
Martyrs Menodora, Metrodora, and Nymphodora, at Nicomedia (09-10).jpg
Martyrs Modestus, Crescentia, and Vitus, at Lucania (06-15).jpg
Martyrs Nikephoros, Antoninus, and Germanus of Caesarea, in Palestine (11-13).jpg
Martyrs of Lazeti (04-29).jpg
Martyrs of Niculitsel (06-04).jpg
Martyrs of the Kvabtakhevi Monastery in Georgia (04-10).jpg
Martyrs Onesiphorus and Porphyrius of Ephesus (11-09).jpg
Martyrs Pamphilius the Presbyter, Valens the Deacon, and those with them, at Caesarea in Palestine (02-16).jpg
Martyrs Patermuthius, Coprius, and Alexander the Soldier, in Egypt (07-09).jpg
Martyrs Peter, Dionysius, Andrew, Paul, and Christina who suffered under Decius (05-18).jpg
Martyrs Philemon, Apollonios, Arrian, and Theonas of Alexandria (12-14).jpg
Martyrs Probus, Tarachus, and Andronicus, at Tarsus in Cilicia (10-12).jpg
Martyrs Processus and Martinian of Rome (04-11).jpg
Martyrs Proclus and Hilary of Ancyra (07-12).jpg
Martyrs Rhipsime and Gaianḗ of Armenia and those with them (09-30).jpg
Martyrs Rufinus the Deacon, Aquilina, and 200 soldiers with them at Sinope (04-07).jpg
Martyrs Sergius and Bacchus in Syria (10-07).jpg
Martyrs Shio, David, Gabriel, and Paul of Akhalkalaki in Georgia (06-01).jpg
Martyrs Sophia, Irene, and Castor of Egypt (09-18).jpg
Martyrs Straton, Philip, Eutychian, and Cyprian, of Nicomedia (08-17).jpg
Martyrs Theodore and his son, John, of Kiev (07-12).jpg
Martyrs Thyrsos, Leukios, and Kallinikos (12-14).jpg
Martyrs Tigrius the Presbyter and Eutropius the Reader, of Constantinople (06-16).jpg
Martyrs Timothy, Agapius, and Thekla, of Palestine (08-19).jpg
Martyrs Trophimus and Eucarpus of Nicomedia (03-18).jpg
Martyrs Trophimus, Sabbatius, and Dorymedon of Synnada (09-19).jpg
Martyrs Valentine and Pasikrates in Moesia, Bulgaria (04-24).jpg
Martyrs Victor and Sosthenes at Chalcedon (09-16).jpg
Martyrs Vitus, Modestus, and Crescentia, at Lucania (05-16).jpg
mary-magdalene.jpg
mary-of-egypt.jpeg
mary-theotokos.jpg
matthew-evangelist.jpg
matthias-apostle.webp
matuska-olga-michael.jpg
maximus-confessor.jpg
Meeting of the Vladimir Icon of the Mother of God (05-21).jpg
Meeting of the Vladimir Icon of the Mother of God in memory of the Saving of Moscow from the Invasion of Khan Achmed (06-23).jpg
Memorial Saturday of Saint Demetrius (10-24).jpg
Midfeast of Pentecost (05-06).jpg
Miracle of the Annunciation Icon of the Mother of God at Ustiug (07-08).jpg
Monastic Martyr Agathangelus of Esphigmenou, Mount Athos (04-19).jpg
Monastic Martyr Anastasia of Rome (10-29).jpg
Monastic Martyr Anastasius the Persian (01-22).jpg
Monastic Martyr and Confessor Stephen the New (11-28).jpg
Monastic Martyr Bademus (Vadim) of Persia (04-09).jpg
Monastic Martyr Dositheus (08-13).jpg
Monastic Martyr Euphrosynus of Blue Jay Lake, Novgorod (03-20).jpg
Monastic Martyr Eustratius of the Kiev Near Caves (03-28).jpg
Monastic Martyr Galacteon of Vologda (09-24).jpg
Monastic Martyr Gideon of Karakalou, Mount Athos (12-30).jpg
moses-prophet.jpg
Murom Icon of the Mother of God (04-12).jpg
Myrrhbearer and Equal of the Apostles Mary Magdalene (07-22).jpg
Nativity of Saint Nicholas the Wonderworker (07-29).jpg
Nativity of the Holy Glorious Prophet, Forerunner and Baptist, John (06-24).jpg
New Hieromartyr Alexis (Benemanskii) of Tver (11-22).jpg
New Hieromartyr Archbishop Thaddeus of Tver (12-18).jpg
New Hieromartyr Demetrius (Benevolenskii) of Tver (11-14).jpg
New Hieromartyr Elias (Gromoglasov) of Tver (11-22).jpg
New Hieromartyr Gregory (Raevskii) of Tver (09-16).jpg
New Hieromartyr Nicholas (Dmitrov) of Tver (02-23).jpg
New Hieromartyr Vladimir (Moshchansky) of Tver (08-25).jpg
New Martyr Angelos of Chios (12-03).jpg
New Martyr Archbishop Andronicus of Perm (06-04).jpg
New Martyr Archpriest Vasily Martysz (05-04).jpg
New Martyr Argyrus (05-11).jpg
New Martyr Auxentius of Constantinople (01-25).jpg
New Martyr Demetrius (01-29).jpg
New Martyr Demetrius of Samarina in Epirus (08-17).jpg
New Martyr George of Iberia (01-02).jpg
New Martyr John the New of Epirus (04-18).jpg
New Martyr John the New of Sochi, who suffered at Belgrade (06-02).jpg
New Martyr John, Archbishop of Riga and Latvia (10-12).jpg
New Martyr Myron of Crete (03-20).jpg
New Martyr Nazarius, Metropolitan of Kutaisi-Gaenati, and his companions, of Georgia (08-14).jpg
New Martyr Niketas of Pojani and Serres (04-04).jpg
New Martyr Nikḗtas of Nisyros near Rhodes (06-21).jpg
New Martyr Triandaphyllus of Stara Zagora (08-08).jpg
New Martyr Vukasin of Klepci, Serbia (05-16).jpg
New Martyr Zlata of Meglena, Bulgaria (10-13).jpg
New Martyrs and Confessors of Butovo (05-09).jpg
New Martyrs Isaac and Joseph of Georgia (09-16).jpg
New Martyrs Raphael, Nicholas, and Irene of Lesbos (04-09).jpg
nicholas-of-myra.jpg
nina-of-georgia.jpg
Nine Martyrs at Cyzicus Theognes, Rufus, Antipater, Theostichus, Artemas, Magnus, Theodotus, Thaumasius, and Philemon (04-29).jpg
nino-equal-to-apostles.jpg
Nun-martyr Barbara (07-18).jpg
Nun-Martyr Eugenia of Rome (12-24).jpg
Opening of the relics of Saint Daniel of Pereyaslavl (12-30).jpg
Opening of the Relics of Venerable Savva of Storozhev, or Zvenigorod (01-19).jpg
paisios-holy-mountain.jpeg
Passion-Bearer Gleb (in Baptism David) (09-05).jpg
peter-paul-apostles.jpg
philip-apostle.jpg
Pimenov Icon of the Mother of God (06-06).jpg
Postfeast of Pentecost — 3rd Day of the Trinity (06-02).jpg
Postfeast of Pentecost — Day of the Holy Spirit (06-01).jpg
Presbyters and Confessors Eugene and Macarius, at Antioch (02-19).jpg
Priestmartyr Alexei (Medvedkov) (07-20).jpg
Priestmartyr Demetrius (Klepinine) (07-20).jpg
Priestmartyr John Kochurov (10-31).jpg
Princess Anna of Novgorod (02-10).jpg
Procession of the Honorable Wood of the Life-Giving Cross of the Lord (First of the three “Feasts of the Savior” in August) (08-01).jpg
Prodromitsa Icon of the Mother of God (07-12).jpg
Prophet Amos (06-15).jpg
Prophet Baruch (09-28).jpg
Prophet Daniel (12-17).jpg
Prophet Elisha (06-14).jpg
Prophet Ezekiel (07-21).jpg
Prophet Habakkuk (12-02).jpg
Prophet Haggai (12-16).jpg
Prophet Hosea (10-17).jpg
Prophet Isaiah (05-09).jpg
Prophet Jeremiah (05-01).jpg
Prophet Joel (10-19).jpg
Prophet Jonah (09-22).jpg
Prophet Micah (01-05).jpg
Prophet Micah (08-14).jpg
Prophet Nahum (12-01).jpg
Prophet Nathan (12-13).jpg
Prophet Nehemiah (12-13).jpg
Prophet Obadiah (Abdia) (11-19).jpg
Prophet Samuel (08-20).jpg
Prophet Solomon (12-13).jpg
Prophet Zachariah (02-08).jpg
Prophet Zephaniah (12-03).jpg
Prophetess Hannah the mother of the Prophet Samuel (12-09).jpg
Protomartyr and Archdeacon Stephen (12-27).jpg
Protomartyr and Equal of the Apostles Thekla (09-24).jpg
Recovery of the Relics (1650) and the Second Glorification (1909) of the Holy Venerable Right-believing Great Princess Anna of Kashin, Wonderworker (06-12).jpg
Recovery of the relics of Saint Job of Pochaev (08-28).jpg
Repose of Saint Alexander Nevsky (11-23).jpg
Repose of Saint Alexis Toth, Confessor and Defender of Orthodoxy in America (05-07).jpg
Repose of Saint Arsenius, Archbishop of Serbia (10-28).jpg
Repose of Saint Cyprian, Metropolitan of Moscow and All Russia (09-16).jpg
Repose of Saint Cyril, Equal of the Apostles and Teacher of the Slavs (02-14).jpg
Repose of Saint Eustathius I, Archbishop of Serbia (01-04).jpg
Repose of Saint Herman, Archbishop of Kazan (11-06).jpg
Repose of Saint Innocent, first Bishop of Irkutsk (11-26).jpg
Repose of Saint Innocent, Metropolitan of Moscow, Enlightener of the Aleuts, Apostle to the Americas (03-31).jpg
Repose of Saint Jacob Netsvetov, Enlightener of the Peoples of Alaska (07-26).jpg
Repose of Saint Job, Patriarch of Moscow and all Russia (06-19).jpg
Repose of Saint John Chrysostom, Archbishop of Constantinople (09-14).jpg
Repose of Saint Jonah, Archbishop of Novgorod (11-05).jpg
Repose of Saint Jonah, Metropolitan of Moscow and All Russia (03-31).jpg
Repose of Saint Nikolai of Zhicha (03-18).jpg
Repose of Saint Peter, Metropolitan of Moscow, Wonderworker of All Russia (12-21).jpg
Repose of Saint Philaret (Drozdov), Metropolitan of Moscow (11-19).jpg
Repose of Saint Raphael, Bishop of Brooklyn (02-27).jpg
Repose of Saint Stephen of Dečani, Serbia (11-11).jpg
Repose of Saint Theodore Yaroslavich, older brother of Saint Alexander Nevsky (06-05).jpg
Repose of Saint Theodosius of Chernigov (02-05).jpg
Repose of Saint Tikhon, Patriarch of Moscow, Enlightener of North America (04-07).jpg
Repose of the Blessed John of Ustiug the Fool-for-Christ (05-29).jpg
Repose of the Blessed Maximus of Moscow (11-11).jpg
Repose of the Holy Apostle and Evangelist John the Theologian (09-26).jpg
Repose of the New-Hieromartyr Cosmas of Aitolia, Equal of the Apostles (08-24).jpg
Right-Believing Prince Roman of Uglich (02-03).jpg
Right-believing Prince Vladimir Yaroslavich of Novgorod (10-04).jpg
Right-believing Prince Wenceslas of the Czech Lands (03-04).jpg
Right-believing Princes Basil and Constantine Vsevolodovich of Yaroslavl (07-03).jpg
Right-believing Tamara, Queen of Georgia (05-01).jpg
Righteous Admiral Theodore Ushakov of the Russian Naval Fleet (10-02).jpg
Righteous Anna the Prophetess and Daughter of Phanuel, who met the Lord at the Temple in Jerusalem (08-28).jpg
Righteous Artemius of Verkola (06-23).jpg
Righteous Benjamin (12-13).jpg
Righteous Child Artemius of Verkola (10-20).jpg
Righteous Deborah (12-13).jpg
Righteous Eudocimus of Cappadocia (07-31).jpg
Righteous Forefather Abraham (10-09).jpg
Righteous Hezekiah (08-28).jpg
Righteous Isaac (12-13).jpg
Righteous Jacob (12-13).jpg
Righteous James the Brother of the Lord (12-27).jpg
Righteous Job the Long-Suffering (05-06).jpg
Righteous Joseph the Patriarch (03-31).jpg
Righteous Joshua, son of Nun (Navi) (09-01).jpg
Righteous Judith (12-13).jpg
Righteous Juliana of Lazarevo, Murom (01-02).jpg
Righteous King Demetrius Tavdadebuli of Georgia (03-12).jpg
Righteous Martha and Mary, the sisters of Lazarus (06-04).jpg
Righteous Martyr Maria (Skobtsova) (07-20).jpg
Righteous Melchizedek, King of Salem (05-22).jpg
Righteous Methodia of Kimolos (10-05).jpg
Righteous Miriam (12-13).jpg
Righteous Mother Olga of Kwethluk–Tanqilria Arrsamquq–Wonderworker, Matushka of All Alaska (10-27).jpg
Righteous Noah (12-13).jpg
Righteous Nonna, mother of Saint Gregory the Theologian (08-05).jpg
Righteous Philaret the Merciful of Amnia in Asia Minor (12-01).jpg
Righteous Priest Aaron (12-13).jpg
Righteous Procopius the Fool-For-Christ and Wonderworker of Ustya, Vologda (07-08).jpg
Righteous Rebecca (12-13).jpg
Righteous Sarah (12-13).jpg
Righteous Simeon, Wonderworker of Verkhoturye (12-18).jpg
Righteous Susanna (12-13).jpg
Righteous Tarasius of Liconium (03-09).jpg
Righteous Theodora, wife of Emperor Theophilus the Iconoclast (02-11).jpg
Righteous Virgin Martyr Glaphyra (04-26).jpg
Royal Martyr Mirdat, King of Kartli (07-08).jpg
Royal Passionbearers Tsar Nicholas (Nikolai), Tsaritsa Alexandra, Tsarevich Aleksy, Grand Duchesses Olga, Tatiana, Maria, Anastasia (07-17).jpg
Saint (John) Tornike of Mount Athos (06-12).jpg
Saint Abraham, Bishop of Charres, Mesopotamia (02-14).jpg
Saint Achilles, Bishop of Larissa (05-15).jpg
Saint Agapitos the Confessor and Wonderworker, Bishop of Synnada in Phrygia (02-18).jpg
Saint Agapitus, Pope of Rome (04-17).jpg
Saint Agathon, Pope of Rome (02-20).jpg
Saint Aidan, Bishop of Lindesfarne (08-31).jpg
Saint Akaki Asistavi of Georgia (05-07).jpg
Saint Alban, Protomartyr of Britain (06-22).jpg
Saint Alexander of Guria (11-08).jpg
Saint Alexander, founder of the Monastery of the “Unsleeping Ones” (07-03).jpg
Saint Alexander, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-30).jpg
Saint Alexei, Metropolitan of Moscow, Wonderworker of All Russia (02-12).jpg
Saint Amand, Abbot of Maastricht (02-06).jpg
Saint Ambrose the Confessor (03-16).jpg
Saint Ambrose, Bishop of Milan (12-07).jpg
Saint Amphilokhios, Bishop of Iconium (11-23).jpg
Saint Anastasia the Patrician of Alexandria (03-10).jpg
Saint Anatolius, Patriarch of Constantinople (07-03).jpg
Saint Andrew, Archbishop of Crete (07-04).jpg
Saint Angelina of Serbia (07-01).jpg
Saint Anna and her son, Saint John, of Constantinople (06-13).jpg
Saint Anthimus of Chios (02-15).jpg
Saint Anthimus the Georgian (09-27).jpg
Saint Anthimus, Bishop of Georgia (06-13).jpg
Saint Anthony of Martkofeli (08-16).jpg
Saint Anthony, founder of Monasticism in Georgia (01-19).jpg
Saint Anthony, Metropolitan of Chqondidi, and Saint Jacob, Elder of Chqondidi (10-13).jpg
Saint Anthony, Patriarch of Constantinople (02-12).jpg
Saint Antipater, Bishop of Bostra, Arabia (06-13).jpg
Saint Apollinaria of Egypt (01-05).jpg
Saint Aquila, Deacon, of the Kiev Caves (01-04).jpg
Saint Arsenius of Cappadocia (10-28).jpg
Saint Arsenius of Iqalto, Georgia (02-06).jpg
Saint Arsenius the Great, Catholicos of Georgia (09-25).jpg
Saint Arsenius, Bishop of Ninotsminda (07-31).jpg
Saint Arsenius, Bishop of Tver (03-02).jpg
Saint Artemon, Bishop of Seleucia (03-24).jpg
Saint Athanasius of Lubensk, Patriarch of Constantinople (05-02).jpg
Saint Athanasius of Meteora (04-20).jpg
Saint Athanasius the Confessor of Constantinople (02-22).jpg
Saint Athanasius the Great, Archbishop of Alexandria (01-18).jpg
Saint Athanasius the Great, Patriarch of Alexandria (05-02).jpg
Saint Athanasius the New, Wonderworker and Archbishop of Christianopolis (05-17).jpg
Saint Augustine of Canterbury, Evangelizer of England (05-26).jpg
Saint Averkios the Wonderworker, Bishop of Hieropolis, Equal of the Apostles (10-22).jpg
Saint Barsanuphius, Bishop of Tver (04-11).jpg
Saint Basil of Georgia, son of King Bagrat III (05-27).jpg
Saint Basil Ratishvili of Georgia (04-18).jpg
Saint Basil the Confessor, Bishop of Parium (04-12).jpg
Saint Basil the Great, Archbishop of Caesarea in Cappadocia (01-01).jpg
Saint Basil, Bishop of Ryazan (07-03).jpg
Saint Basil, Bishop of Zakholmsk in Montenegro, Serbia (04-29).jpg
Saint Bassianus, Bishop of Lodi in Liguria (06-10).jpg
Saint Boris (in Baptism Michael), Equal of the Apostles, Prince and Baptizer of Bulgaria (05-02).jpg
Saint Brannock of Braunton (01-07).jpg
Saint Brendan the Navigator (05-16).jpg
Saint Brihtwald of Wilton (01-22).jpg
Saint Bucolus, Bishop of Smyrna (02-06).jpg
Saint Callinicus, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-23).jpg
Saint Cedd of Lastingham (01-07).jpg
Saint Celestine, Pope of Rome (04-08).jpg
Saint Christódoulos, Wonderworker of Patmos (03-16).jpg
Saint Claudia Procula (10-27).jpg
Saint Clement of Ochrid, Equal of the Apostles, Bishop of Greater Macedonia, and his companions Nahum, Savva, Gorazd and Angelar (07-27).jpg
Saint Clement of Ochrid, Equal of the Apostles, Bishop of Greater Macedonia, and his companions Nahum, Savva, Gorazd and Angelar (11-25).jpg
Saint Colman of Lindesfarne (02-18).jpg
Saint Columba of Iona, Enlightener of Scotland (06-09).jpg
Saint Constantine Brancoveanu and those with him (08-16).jpg
Saint Cosmas the Hymnographer, Bishop of Maiuma (10-12).jpg
Saint Cosmas, Bishop of Chalcedon, and his fellow ascetic, Saint Auxentius (04-18).jpg
Saint Cuthbert, Wonderworker of Britain (03-20).jpg
Saint Cyril of Astrakhan (03-18).jpg
Saint Cyril, Archbishop of Alexandria (01-18).jpg
Saint Cyril, Archbishop of Alexandria (06-09).jpg
Saint Cyril, Archbishop of Jerusalem (03-18).jpg
Saint Cyril, Bishop of Catania (03-21).jpg
Saint Cyril, Bishop of Turov (04-28).jpg
Saint Damiane (Demetrius), King and Hymnographer (05-23).jpg
Saint Daniel II, Archbishop of Serbia (12-20).jpg
Saint David Gareji, and Venerable Lucian, spiritual son of Saint David (06-09).jpg
Saint David of Thessaloniki (06-26).jpg
Saint David, Bishop of Wales (03-01).jpg
Saint Demetrius (Dimitri), Metropolitan of Rostov (10-28).jpg
Saint Demetrius of Basarabov (10-27).jpg
Saint Dionysios the Rhetorician and his disciple Saint Mētrophánēs (07-09).jpg
Saint Dionysius, Archbishop of Suzdal (06-26).jpg
Saint Dometian, Bishop of Melitene (01-10).jpg
Saint Domna of Tomsk (10-16).jpg
Saint Domnina the Younger of Syria (03-01).jpg
Saint Donatus, Bishop of Euroea in Epirus (04-30).jpg
Saint Dositheus of Tbilisi (01-25).jpg
Saint Doulas, Passion-Bearer of Egypt (06-15).jpg
Saint Eanswythe, Abbess of Folkestone (08-31).jpg
Saint Elena of Serbia (10-04).jpg
Saint Elian, Missionary to Cornwall, England (01-13).jpg
Saint Elizabeth, Wonderworker of Constantinople (04-24).jpg
Saint Emilian the Confessor, Bishop of Cyzicus (01-08).jpg
Saint Endellion, recluse of Cornwall (04-29).jpg
Saint Ephraim the Great of Atsquri (04-15).jpg
Saint Ephraim the Lesser (01-18).jpg
Saint Epiphanius, Bishop of Cyprus (05-12).jpg
Saint Euboula, mother of Saint Panteleimon (03-30).jpg
Saint Eulogius, Archbishop of Alexandria (02-13).jpg
Saint Eumenius, Bishop of Gortyna (09-18).jpg
Saint Euphrosynos the Cook of Alexandria (09-11).jpg
Saint Euphrosynē, Great Princess of Moscow (05-17).jpg
Saint Eustathius, Archbishop of Antioch (02-21).jpg
Saint Euthymios, Patriarch of Trnovo (01-20).jpg
Saint Euthymius (01-22).jpg
Saint Euthymius (Takaishvili) (01-03).jpg
Saint Euthymius the Confessor (01-20).jpg
Saint Euthymius the Elder of Saint John the Baptist Monastery (08-08).jpg
Saint Euthymius the New, Founder of the Ivḗron Monastery, and his fellow Georgian Saints of Mount Athos (05-13).jpg
Saint Eutychius, Bishop of Melitene (05-28).jpg
Saint Eutychius, Patriarch of Constantinople (04-06).jpg
Saint Evagrisi, disciple of Saint Shio (02-04).jpg
Saint Fantinus of Calabria (08-30).jpg
Saint Felix of Burgundy, Bishop of Dunwich, Enlightener of East Anglia (03-08).jpg
Saint Finan of Lindisfarne (02-17).jpg
Saint Flavian the Confessor, Patriarch of Constantinople (02-18).jpg
Saint Gabriel, Bishop of Imereti (01-25).jpg
Saint Gelasius of Rimet (06-30).jpg
Saint Gennadius, Archbishop of Novgorod (12-04).jpg
Saint Gennadius, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-31).jpg
Saint George (John) of Georgia (01-21).jpg
Saint George Matskevereli of Georgia (04-02).jpg
Saint George the Confessor and Bishop of Antioch, in Pisidia (04-19).jpg
Saint George the Confessor, Bishop of Mytilene (04-07).jpg
Saint George the God-Bearer (07-03).jpg
Saint George, New Martyr of Sofia (02-11).jpg
Saint Germanus of Dacia Pontica (Dobrogea) (02-28).jpg
Saint Gregory Dialogus, Pope of Rome (03-12).jpg
Saint Gregory of Chandzoe, Georgia (10-05).jpg
Saint Gregory Palamas, Archbishop of Thessalonica (11-14).jpg
Saint Gregory the Theologian, Archbishop of Constantinople (01-25).jpg
Saint Gregory, Archbishop of Alexandria (11-05).jpg
Saint Gregory, Bishop of Agrigentum (11-23).jpg
Saint Gregory, Bishop of Nyssa (01-10).jpg
Saint Gregory, Wonderworker of Neocaesarea (11-17).jpg
Saint Helen of Serbia (10-30).jpg
Saint Hilarion of Tvali (07-24).jpg
Saint Hilarion the New of Georgia (02-14).jpg
Saint Hosius the Confessor, Bishop of Córdoba (08-27).jpg
Saint Hypatius of Gangra (11-16).jpg
Saint Hypatius the Wonderworker, Bishop of Gangra (03-31).jpg
Saint Ignatius Brianchaninov, Bishop of the Caucasus and Stavropol (04-30).jpg
Saint Illyricus of Mount Myrsinon in the Peloponnesus (04-03).jpg
Saint Innocent of Komél and Vologda disciple of Saint Nilus of Sora (03-19).jpg
Saint Irene Chrysovolantou (07-28).jpg
Saint Isaac the Syrian, Abbot of Spoleto (04-12).jpg
Saint Isaac the Syrian, Bishop of Nineveh (01-28).jpg
Saint Isidore, Bishop of Seville (04-04).jpg
Saint Ita, Hermitess of Killeedy (01-15).jpg
Saint James the Confessor, Bishop of Catania (03-21).jpg
Saint James, Bishop of Nisibis (01-13).jpg
Saint Jerome (Hieronymus) of Stridon (06-15).jpg
Saint Jesse, Bishop of Tsilkani, Georgia (12-02).jpg
Saint Joanna the Myrrhbearer (06-27).jpg
Saint Joasaph, Bishop of Belgorod (12-10).jpg
Saint John (Chrysostom) IV, Catholicos of Georgia (03-03).jpg
Saint John Chimchimeli the Philosopher (02-10).jpg
Saint John Chrysostom, Archbishop of Constantinople (11-13).jpg
Saint John Jacob the Chozebite (08-05).jpg
Saint John Maximovitch, Metropolitan of Tobolsk (06-10).jpg
Saint John of Galesh (10-21).jpg
Saint John of Georgia (09-21).jpg
Saint John of Khakhuli the Oqropiri, also called Chrysostom (03-10).jpg
Saint John of Prislop (09-13).jpg
Saint John Shavteli, Bishop of Gaenati and Saint Eulogius, Prophet and Fool-for-Christ of Salosi (04-01).jpg
Saint John the Chozebite, Bishop of Caesarea, Palestine (10-03).jpg
Saint John the Faster, Patriarch of Constantinople (09-02).jpg
Saint John the Merciful, Patriarch of Alexandria (11-12).jpg
Saint John the Russian and Confessor, whose relics are on the island of Euboia (05-27).jpg
Saint John the Wonderworker, Archbishop of Novgorod (09-07).jpg
Saint John Zedazeni of Zaden, Georgia, with his 12 disciples (05-07).jpg
Saint John [Maximovitch], Archbishop of Shanghai and San Francisco (07-02).jpg
Saint John, Bishop of Suzdal (10-15).jpg
Saint John, Bishop of the Goths in the Crimea (06-26).jpg
Saint John, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-30).jpg
Saint John-Vladimir, Prince of Bulgaria, Greatmartyr, and Miracle-worker (05-22).jpg
Saint Jonah the Presbyter, father of Saint Theophanes the Hymnographer and Theodore Graptus (09-22).jpg
Saint Jonah, Metropolitan of Moscow (06-15).jpg
Saint Joseph of Serbia (04-20).jpg
Saint Joseph the Confessor of Maramures (04-24).jpg
Saint Joseph the New of Partos, Metropolitan of Timishoara (Romania) (09-15).jpg
Saint Joseph, and his companions, of Damascus (07-10).jpg
Saint Joseph, Bishop of Thessalonica, and brother of Saint Theodore of Studion (01-26).jpg
Saint Joseph, Catholicos of Georgia (10-17).jpg
Saint Jotham Zedgenidze (10-30).jpg
Saint Julian, Bishop of Cenomanis (Le Mans), Gaul (07-13).jpg
Saint Julius, Presbyter of Novara, and his brother, Saint Julian the Deacon (06-21).jpg
Saint Just of Penwith (07-13).jpg
Saint Justinian the Emperor (11-14).jpg
Saint Kaikhosro the Georgian (06-16).jpg
Saint Kentigern, first Bishop of Glasgow, Scotland (01-14).jpg
Saint Kevin of Glendalough (06-03).jpg
Saint Kristo the Gardener of Albania (02-12).jpg
Saint Laurence, Recluse of the Kiev Far Caves (01-20).jpg
Saint Leander of Seville (02-27).jpg
Saint Leo the Great, Pope of Rome (02-18).jpg
Saint Leo, Bishop of Catania in Sicily (02-20).jpg
Saint Leontius of Rădăuţi (07-01).jpg
Saint Liberius, Pope of Rome (08-27).jpg
Saint Luke, Archbishop of Simferopol (06-11).jpg
Saint Lydia of Philippi (05-20).jpg
Saint Macarius (01-24).jpg
Saint Macarius the Roman of Mesopotamia (10-23).jpg
Saint Macarius, Metropolitan of Moscow and All Russia (12-30).jpg
Saint Mamai, Catholicos of Georgia (05-03).jpg
Saint Marcian of Cyrrhus (11-02).jpg
Saint Mardarije (Uskokovic) of Libertyville (12-12).jpg
Saint Mariamne the sister of the Apostle Philip (02-17).jpg
Saint Mark, Archbishop of Ephesus (01-19).jpg
Saint Martin the Confessor, Pope of Rome (04-14).jpg
Saint Martin the Merciful, Bishop of Tours (10-12).jpg
Saint Martin the Merciful, Bishop of Tours (11-11).jpg
Saint Maruthas, Bishop of Martyropolis in Mesopotamia (02-16).jpg
Saint Matrona of Moscow (05-02).jpg
Saint Maximian, Patriarch of Constantinople (04-21).jpg
Saint Melchizedek I, Catholicos-Patriarch of All Georgia (10-01).jpg
Saint Meletius the New (09-01).jpg
Saint Meletius, Archbishop of Antioch (02-12).jpg
Saint Meletius, Archbishop of Khar'kov and Akhtyrsk (02-12).jpg
Saint Menas, Bishop of Polotsk (06-20).jpg
Saint Menas, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-25).jpg
Saint Methodius, Equal of the Apostles, Archbishop of Moravia, Enlightener of the Slavs (04-06).jpg
Saint Methodius, Patriarch of Constantinople (06-14).jpg
Saint Metrophanes (in schema Macarius), Bishop of Voronezh (11-23).jpg
Saint Metrophanes, first Patriarch of Constantinople (06-04).jpg
Saint Michael the Confessor, Bishop of Synnada (05-23).jpg
Saint Michael, first Metropolitan of Kiev (06-15).jpg
Saint Michael, first Metropolitan of Kiev (09-30).jpg
Saint Modestos, Archbishop of Jerusalem (12-18).jpg
Saint Moloug of Lismore (06-25).jpg
Saint Monica (05-04).jpg
Saint Moses, Archbishop of Novgorod (01-25).jpg
Saint Mstislav (George), Prince of Novgorod (06-14).jpg
Saint Myron the Wonderworker, Bishop of Crete (08-08).jpg
Saint Nahum of Ochrid, disciple of Saints Cyril and Methodius, Equal of the Apostles (12-23).jpg
Saint Nahum of Ochrid, disciple of Saints Cyril and Methodius, Equals of the Apostles (06-20).jpg
Saint Nectarius Kephalas, Metropolitan of Pentapolis (11-09).jpg
Saint Nicanor, Wonderworker of Mount Calistratus (08-07).jpg
Saint Nicholas Kandaurov (02-17).jpg
Saint Nicholas, Catholicos of Georgia (02-18).jpg
Saint Nicholas, Enlightener of Japan (02-03).jpg
Saint Nikephoros the Confessor, Patriarch of Constantinople (06-02).jpg
Saint Nikephoros the Leper (01-04).jpg
Saint Niketas, Bishop of Chalcedon (05-28).jpg
Saint Nikḗtas, Bishop of Novgorod, Recluse of the Kiev Far Caves (05-14).jpg
Saint Nino (Nina), Equal of the Apostles, Enlightener of Georgia (01-14).jpg
Saint Niphon, Bishop of Constantia, Cyprus (12-23).jpg
Saint Niphon, Bishop of Novgorod (04-08).jpg
Saint Niphon, Patriarch of Constantinople (08-11).jpg
Saint Oleg, Prince of Briansk (09-20).jpg
Saint Onuphrius of Saint David Gareji Monastery, Georgia (09-29).jpg
Saint Oswald, king and martyr (08-05).jpg
Saint Paisius of Uglich (01-08).jpg
Saint Panaretus of Cyprus (05-01).jpg
Saint Parthenios, Bishop of Lampsakos (02-07).jpg
Saint Patrick, Bishop of Armagh, Enlightener of Ireland (03-17).jpg
Saint Paul the Confessor, Archbishop of Constantinople (11-06).jpg
Saint Paul, Physician of Corinth (06-28).jpg
Saint Paula (01-26).jpg
Saint Peter of Cetinje (10-18).jpg
Saint Peter of Korisha (06-05).jpg
Saint Peter the Tax-Collector (09-22).jpg
Saint Peter the Wonderworker, Bishop of Argos (05-03).jpg
Saint Peter, Prince of Ordinsk, Rostov (06-30).jpg
Saint Phanourius (08-27).jpg
Saint Philip, Abbot of Irap Near Novgorod (11-14).jpg
Saint Philotheus the Presbyter in Asia Minor (09-15).jpg
Saint Phoebe the Deaconess at Cenchreae near Corinth (09-03).jpg
Saint Photius, Metropolitan of Kiev (07-02).jpg
Saint Photius, Patriarch of Constantinople (02-06).jpg
Saint Pitirim, Bishop of Tambov (07-28).jpg
Saint Plato the Confessor of Studion (04-05).jpg
Saint Platonis of Nisibis, Syria (04-06).jpg
Saint Porphyrius, Bishop of Gaza (02-26).jpg
Saint Prochorus of Georgia (02-12).jpg
Saint Proclus, Archbishop of Constantinople (11-20).jpg
Saint Quiricus (Kḗrykos) and his mother Julitta (07-15).jpg
Saint Rostislav, Prince of Great Moravia (05-11).jpg
Saint Sabbatius of Tver (03-02).jpg
Saint Sampson the Hospitable of Constantinople (06-27).jpg
Saint Sarmean, Catholicos of Kartli, Georgia (08-21).jpg
Saint Sava II, Archbishop of Serbia (02-08).jpg
Saint Savva I, first Archbishop of Serbia (01-14).jpg
Saint Savva of Pskov (08-28).jpg
Saint Sebastiana the Martyr, disciple of Saint Paul the Apostle, at Heraclea (09-16).jpg
Saint Seraphim of Labodeia (05-06).jpg
Saint Serapion of Zarzma (10-29).jpg
Saint Serapion, Archbishop of Novgorod (03-16).jpg
Saint Serapion, Bishop of Thmuis in Lower Egypt (03-21).jpg
Saint Seririol of Wales (02-01).jpg
Saint Shalva of Akhaltsikhe (06-17).jpg
Saint Simeon of Egypt (04-05).jpg
Saint Simeon Stylites, the Elder (09-01).jpg
Saint Sophronius, Bishop of Irkutsk (03-30).jpg
Saint Sophronius, Patriarch of Jerusalem (03-11).jpg
Saint Spyridon the Wonderworker, Bishop of Tremithus (12-12).jpg
Saint Stephen Milutin of Serbia (10-30).jpg
Saint Stephen Stiljianovitch of Serbia (10-04).jpg
Saint Stephen the Confessor, Archbishop of Sourozh, Crimea (12-15).jpg
Saint Stephen the Great (07-02).jpg
Saint Stephen Urosh, King of Serbia (12-02).jpg
Saint Stephen, Bishop of Perm (04-26).jpg
Saint Sylvester, Pope of Rome (01-02).jpg
Saint Tabitha the Widow, raised from the dead by the Apostle Peter (10-25).jpg
Saint Tarasius, Archbishop of Constantinople (02-25).jpg
Saint Tbeli Abuseridze (08-17).jpg
Saint Theoctistus the Confessor (11-20).jpg
Saint Theodora of Sihla (08-07).jpg
Saint Theodora the Empress (11-14).jpg
Saint Theodore of Ajareli (01-26).jpg
Saint Theodore of Edessa, Mesopotamia (07-19).jpg
Saint Theodore of Tarsus, Archbishop of Canterbury (09-19).jpg
Saint Theodore the Sykeote, Bishop of Anastasiopolis (04-22).jpg
Saint Theodore, Archbishop of Rostov (11-28).jpg
Saint Theodore, Bishop of Edessa (07-09).jpg
Saint Theodore, Prince of Smolensk and Yaroslav, and his sons Saints David and Constantine (09-19).jpg
Saint Theognostus, Metropolitan of Kiev and All Russia (03-14).jpg
Saint Theonas of Egypt (04-05).jpg
Saint Theophan the Recluse, Bishop of Tambov (01-10).jpg
Saint Theophanes the Confessor and Hymnographer, Bishop of Nicea (10-11).jpg
Saint Theophanó the Wonderworker, wife of Emperor Leo the Wise (12-16).jpg
Saint Theophilus the Confessor of Bulgaria (10-10).jpg
Saint Theophylactus of Ochrid (12-31).jpg
Saint Theophylactus, Bishop of Nicomedia (03-08).jpg
Saint Tikhon, Bishop of Amathus in Cyprus (06-16).jpg
Saint Tikhon, Bishop of Voronezh, Wonderworker of Zadonsk and All Russia (08-13).jpg
Saint Triphyllius, Bishop of Leucosia (Nicosia), Cyprus (06-13).jpg
Saint Tryphon, Patriarch of Constantinople (04-19).jpg
Saint Tsotne Dadiani the Confessor (07-30).jpg
Saint Vakhtang Gorgasali, King of Georgia (11-30).jpg
Saint Varnava (Nastic) (11-12).jpg
Saint Veronica (Bernice), the woman with the issue of blood (07-12).jpg
Saint Vincent of Lerins (05-24).jpg
Saint Vladimir, Metropolitan of Kiev and Gallich (01-25).jpg
Saint Vladislav of Serbia (09-24).jpg
Saint Vsevolod (in Baptism Gabriel), Wonderworker of Pskov (02-11).jpg
Saint Zosimas II of Kumurdo (05-01).jpg
Saints Archilius and Luarsaab (01-28).jpg
Saints Asclepius and James of Syria (02-27).jpg
Saints Eutychius and Florentius of Nursia (08-23).jpg
Saints John, Stephen, and Isaiah of Georgia (11-04).jpg
Saints Martinian, Zoe, and Photina of Caesarea in Palestine (02-13).jpg
Saints Michael and Arsenius of Ulompo, Georgia (05-03).jpg
Saints Peter and Fevronia (tonsured David and Euphrosyne), Wonderworkers of Murom (06-25).jpg
Saints Pimen of Salosi and Anton Meskhi, Enlighteners of Dagestan and the North Caucasus people (03-16).jpg
Saints Salome of Ujarma and Perozhavra of Sivnia (01-15).jpg
Saints Xanthippi and Polyxeni of Spain (09-23).jpg
Saturday of Cheesefare Commemoration of all our God-bearing Fathers and Mothers who shone forth in asceticism (02-21).jpg
Second Day of the Nativity of our Lord (12-26).jpg
Second Translation of the relics of Saint Herman, Archbishop of Kazan (06-23).jpg
seraphim-of-sarov.jpeg
Seven Arrows Icon of the Mother of God (06-07).jpg
silouan-the-athonite.jpg
simon-zealot.jpg
spyridon-of-tremithus.jpg
stephen-protomartyr.jpg
Sunday before the Nativity (12-20).jpg
Sunday of Cheesefare Expulsion of Adam from Paradise (02-22).jpg
Sunday of Meatfare of the Last Judgment (02-15).jpg
Sunday of the Blind Man (05-17).jpg
Sunday of the Forefathers (12-13).jpg
Sunday of the Holy Myrrhbearing Women with the Noble Joseph (04-26).jpg
Sunday of the Paralytic (05-03).jpg
Sunday of the Prodigal Son (02-08).jpg
Sunday of the Publican and the PhariseeBeginning of the Lenten Triodion (02-01).jpg
Sunday of the Samaritan Woman (05-10).jpg
Sunday of Zacchaeus (01-25).jpg
Synaxis of All Saints (06-07).jpg
Synaxis of All Saints of Alaska (09-24).jpg
Synaxis of the Archangel Gabriel (03-26).jpg
Synaxis of the Archangel Gabriel (07-13).jpg
Synaxis of the Archangel Michael and the Other Bodiless Powers (11-08).jpg
Synaxis of the Ecumenical Teachers and Hierarchs Basil the Great, Gregory the Theologian, and John Chrysostom (01-30).jpg
Synaxis of the Hierarchs of Kazan (10-04).jpg
Synaxis of the Hierarchs of Moscow (10-05).jpg
Synaxis of the Holy Glorious Prophet, Forerunner and Baptist John (01-07).jpg
Synaxis of the Holy, Glorious and All-Praised Twelve Apostles (06-30).jpg
Synaxis of the Most Holy Mother of God (12-26).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Belarus (06-14).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Radonezh (07-06).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Rostov (05-23).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Siberia (06-10).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Solovki Monastery (08-09).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of the Kiev Caves, whose relics repose in the Far Caves of Venerable Theodosius (08-28).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Tula (09-22).jpg
Synaxis of the Saints of Vladimir (06-23).jpg
Synaxis of the Seventy Apostles (01-04).jpg
Synaxis of the Venerable Fathers of Optina (10-11).jpg
Synaxis of the Venerable Fathers of the Kiev Caves Lavra (03-08).jpg
Synaxis of the Venerable Fathers of the Kiev Near Caves (09-28).jpg
Synaxis of the “Axion Estin” Icon of the Mother of God (06-11).jpg
Tambov (Utkino) Icon of the Mother of God (04-16).jpg
The Adoration of the Magi Melchior, Caspar, and Balthasar (12-25).jpg
The Annunciation of our Most Holy Lady, the Theotokos and Ever-Virgin Mary (03-25).jpg
The Ascension of our Lord (05-21).jpg
The Beheading of the Holy Glorious Prophet, Forerunner, and Baptist John (08-29).jpg
The Circumcision of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ (01-01).jpg
The Discovery of the Relics of Venerable Zosimas, Abbot of Vorbozomsk (11-07).jpg
The Dormition of our Most Holy Lady the Mother of God and Ever-Virgin Mary (08-15).jpg
The Holy Glorious and All-Praised Leader of the Apostles, Paul (06-29).jpg
The Holy Glorious and All-Praised Leader of the Apostles, Peter (06-29).jpg
The Holy Glorious and All-Praised Leaders of the Apostles, Peter and Paul (06-29).jpg
The Holy Hieromartyrs of Cherson Basil, Ephraim, Capito, Eugene, Aetherius, Elpidius, and Agathodorus (03-07).jpg
The Holy Right-believing Tsarevich Demetrios of Uglich and Moscow (05-15).jpg
The Holy Transfiguration of our Lord God and Savior Jesus Christ (the Second “Feast of the Savior” in August) (08-06).jpg
The Life Giving Fountain of the Mother of God (04-04).jpg
The Meeting of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ in the Temple (02-02).jpg
The Meeting of the Mother of God and Saint Elizabeth (03-30).jpg
The Nativity of our Lord God and Savior Jesus Christ (12-25).jpg
The Nativity of our Most Holy Lady the Mother of God and Ever-Virgin Mary (09-08).jpg
The Placing of the Cincture (Sash) of the Mother of God (08-31).jpg
The Placing of the Honorable Robe of the Lord at Moscow (07-10).jpg
The Placing of the Honorable Robe of the Most Holy Mother of God at Blachernae (07-02).jpg
The Protection of our Most Holy Lady the Mother of God and Ever-Virgin Mary (10-01).jpg
The Raising of Lazarus (Lazarus Saturday) (04-04).jpg
The Three Holy Youths Ananias, Azarias and Misael (12-17).jpg
The Universal Exaltation of the Precious and Life-Giving Cross (09-14).jpg
Third Day of the Nativity of our Lord (12-27).jpg
thomas-apostle.jpg
Transfer of the relics of Saint Paraskevḗ the New (06-13).jpg
transfiguration.jpg
Translation of the Dormition Icon of the Mother of God from Constantinople to the Kiev Caves, Far Caves (05-03).jpg
Translation of the Image “Not-Made-By-Hands” of our Lord Jesus Christ from Edessa to Constantinople, the Third “Feast of the Savior in August” (08-16).jpg
Translation of the Ivḗron Icon of the Mother of God to Moscow (10-13).jpg
Translation of the relics of Blessed James of Borovichi, Wonderworker of Novgorod (10-23).jpg
Translation of the relics of Blessed Vsevolod (in Baptism Gabriel), Prince of Pskov (04-22).jpg
Translation of the relics of Hieromartyr Philip, Metropolitan of Moscow (07-03).jpg
Translation of the Relics of Martyrs Michael and his councilor, Theodore, of Chernígov (02-14).jpg
Translation of the relics of Righteous Simeon of Verkhoturye (09-12).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Alexander Nevsky (08-30).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Gurias, Archbishop of Kazan (06-20).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Hilarion, Bishop of Meglin in Bulgaria (10-21).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Job, Patriarch of Moscow and All Russia (04-05).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint John Chrysostom, Archbishop of Constantinople (01-27).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Lazarus “of the Four Days in the Tomb”, Bishop of Kiteia, Cyprus (10-17).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Maximus the Confessor (08-13).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Nicholas the Wonderworker from Myra to Bari (05-09).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Nikephoros, Patriarch of Constantinople (03-13).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Nikolai of Zhicha (04-20).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Peter, Metropolitan of Moscow and All Russia (08-24).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Savva, first Archbishop of Serbia (05-06).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Sophronius, Bishop of Irkutsk (06-30).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Theodore the Sykeote (06-15).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saint Tikhon of Luchov, Kostroma (06-26).jpg
Translation of the relics of Saints Cyprian, Photius, and Jonah, Metropolitans of Moscow and All Russia (05-27).jpg
Translation of the “Blachernae” Icon of the Mother of God to Russia (07-07).jpg
Translation of the “Staro Rus” Icon of the Mother of God in Triumph to Russia (09-18).jpg
Venerable Barlaam of Shenkursk (06-19).jpg
Venerable Barlaam, Abbot of Khutyn, Novgorod (11-06).jpg
Venerable Barnabas, Abbot of Vetluga (06-11).jpg
Venerable Barsanuphius of Optina (04-01).jpg
Venerable Barsanuphius the Great and John the Prophet (02-06).jpg
Venerable Basil the Confessor, companion of Venerable Procopius at Decapolis (02-28).jpg
Venerable Bede, the Church Historian (05-27).jpg
Venerable Benedict of Nursia (03-14).jpg
Venerable Bessarion, Wonderworker of Egypt (06-06).jpg
Venerable Botolph of Iken (06-17).jpg
Venerable Brigid (Bridget) of Ireland (02-01).jpg
Venerable Cassian and Gregory, Abbots of Avnezh, Vologda (06-15).jpg
Venerable Chariton the Confessor, Abbot of Palestine (09-28).jpg
Venerable Cherimon (Chaeremon) of Egypt (08-16).jpg
Venerable Christodoulos the Philosopher (08-18).jpg
Venerable Comgall of Bangor (05-10).jpg
Venerable Confessor John Psykhaitis (05-26).jpg
Venerable Constantine of Synnada (12-26).jpg
Venerable Constantine, (in baptism Yaroslav), with his children Michael and Theodore, Wonderworkers of Murom (05-21).jpg
Venerable Cornelius, Abbot of Komel, Vologda (05-19).jpg
Venerable Cornelius, Abbot of Paleostrov (05-19).jpg
Venerable Cosmas of Yakhrom (02-18).jpg
Venerable Cyril the Wonderworker, Abbot of Novoezersk, Novgorod (02-04).jpg
Venerable Cyril, Igoumen of White Lake (06-09).jpg
Venerable Dalmatus the Ascetic of the Dalmatian Monastery at Constantinople (08-03).jpg
Venerable Damian the Healer, Jeremiah, and Matthew, Clairvoyants, of the Kiev Caves (10-05).jpg
Venerable Damian, Ascetic of the Syrian Deserts (02-23).jpg
Venerable Daniel the Hesychast (12-18).jpg
Venerable Daniel the Stylite of Constantinople (12-11).jpg
Venerable Daniel, Abbot of Pereslavl-Zalessky (04-07).jpg
Venerable Demetrios, Wonderworker of Priluki, Vologda (02-11).jpg
Venerable Diodoros, Igoumen of George Hill (11-20).jpg
Venerable Dionysius of Aegina (12-17).jpg
Venerable Dionysius of Olympus (01-24).jpg
Venerable Dionysius the Recluse of the Kiev Caves (10-03).jpg
Venerable Dionysius, Abbot of Glushitsa, Vologda (06-01).jpg
Venerable Dionysius, Archimandrite of Saint Sergius’ Monastery (05-12).jpg
Venerable Dodo of the Saint David-Gareji Monastery, Georgia (05-17).jpg
Venerable Dragutin (Theoctistus in Monasticism) of Serbia (10-30).jpg
Venerable Eleazar of Anzersk Island, Solovki (01-13).jpg
Venerable Elias of Murom, Wonderworker of the Kiev Near Caves (12-19).jpg
Venerable Elisha of Suma, Solovki (06-14).jpg
Venerable Ephraim the Syrian (01-28).jpg
Venerable Ephraim the Wonderworker, Abbot of Novy Torg (01-28).jpg
Venerable Erasmus of Ochrid (06-02).jpg
Venerable Erasmus of the Kiev Near Caves (02-24).jpg
Venerable Eudokia (in monasticism Euphrosyne), Grand Duchess of Moscow (07-07).jpg
Venerable Euphrosyne of Alexandria (09-25).jpg
Venerable Euphrosyne, Abbess of Polotsk (05-23).jpg
Venerable Euphrosynē of Suzdal (09-18).jpg
Venerable Euphrosynē of Suzdal (09-25).jpg
Venerable Eupraxia of Tabenna, in Egypt (01-12).jpg
Venerable Eusebius the Hermit of Syria (02-15).jpg
Venerable Euthymius of Suzdal (04-01).jpg
Venerable Euthymius the Great (01-20).jpg
Venerable Euthymius the New of Thessalonica, and Monk of Mount Athos (10-15).jpg
Venerable Euthymius the Schemamonk (01-20).jpg
Venerable Euthymius, Enlightener of Karelia, Finland and the Righteous Anthony and Felix (04-18).jpg
Venerable Evanthia (09-01).jpg
Venerable Father Zosima, Bishop of Babylon (06-04).jpg
Venerable Fathers and Mothers of the Klarjeti Wilderness (10-05).jpg
Venerable Gabriel of Atonelni (11-04).jpg
Venerable Gabriel the Georgian of Mount Athos (07-12).jpg
Venerable Gabriel, Founder of Lesnov Monastery in Bulgaria (01-15).jpg
Venerable Genevieve of Paris (01-03).jpg
Venerable Gennadius of Kostroma (01-23).jpg
Venerable Gennadius of Vatopedi, Mount Athos (11-17).jpg
Venerable George of Mount Athos (06-27).jpg
Venerable George of Mount Maleon in the Peloponnesus (04-04).jpg
Venerable George the Builder (07-28).jpg
Venerable George the Chozebite, Abbot (01-08).jpg
Venerable George the Scribe, and Venerable Savva, of Khakhuli (12-19).jpg
Venerable Gerasimus of the Jordan (03-04).jpg
Venerable Gerasimus of Vologda (03-04).jpg
Venerable Gerasimus the New Ascetic of Cephalonia (08-16).jpg
Venerable Gerontius the Canonarch of the Kiev Far Caves (04-01).jpg
Venerable Gregory the Byzantine (04-06).jpg
Venerable Gregory the Decapolite (11-20).jpg
Venerable Gregory the Iconographer of the Kiev Near Caves (08-08).jpg
Venerable Gregory, Wonderworker of the Kiev Near Caves (01-08).jpg
Venerable Hellius of Egypt (07-14).jpg
Venerable Hilarion the Great (10-21).jpg
Venerable Hilarion the New, Abbot of Pelekete (03-28).jpg
Venerable Hilarion the New, Abbot of the Dalmatian Monastery (06-06).jpg
Venerable Hilarion the Schemamonk of the Kiev Caves (10-21).jpg
Venerable Hilarion the Wonderworker, Monk of Thessalonica (11-19).jpg
Venerable Hypatius the Healer of the Kiev Caves (03-31).jpg
Venerable Isaac the Ascetic of the Dalmatian Monastery at Constantinople (08-03).jpg
Venerable Isaac the Confessor, Founder of the Dalmatian Monastery at Constantinople (03-22).jpg
Venerable Isaac the Recluse of the Kiev Near Caves (02-14).jpg
Venerable Isaac, Founder of Dalmátos Monastery at Constantinople (05-30).jpg
Venerable Isidore of Pelusium (02-04).jpg
Venerable Isidore the Fool-For-Christ and Wonderworker of Rostov (05-14).jpg
Venerable James, Abbot of Zheleznoborov (04-11).jpg
Venerable Joannicius of Devic (12-02).jpg
Venerable Joannicius the Great (11-04).jpg
Venerable Joasaph, son of Saint Abenner the King (08-26).jpg
Venerable John (Koukouzelis) the Hymnographer of Mount Athos (10-01).jpg
Venerable John Calabytes “the Hut-Dweller” (01-15).jpg
Venerable John Cassian the Roman (02-28).jpg
Venerable John Climacus of Sinai, Author of “the Ladder” (03-30).jpg
Venerable John of Damascus (12-04).jpg
Venerable John of the Ancient Caves in Palestine (04-19).jpg
Venerable John the Anchorite of Egypt (03-29).jpg
Venerable John the Georgian of Mount Athos (07-12).jpg
Venerable John, Ascetic of the Syrian Deserts (02-23).jpg
Venerable John, Bishop of Manglisi (03-28).jpg
Venerable John, disciple of Venerable Gregory of Decapolis (04-18).jpg
Venerable John-Barsanuphius, Bishop of Damascus (02-28).jpg
Venerable Jonah, Abbot of Klimetzk (06-06).jpg
Venerable Joseph the Elder and Wonderworker of Khevi, Georgia (10-07).jpg
Venerable Joseph the Hymnographer (04-04).jpg
Venerable Joseph the Much-Ailing, of the Kiev Far Caves (04-04).jpg
Venerable Joseph the Wonderworker, Igumen of Volokolamsk (10-18).jpg
Venerable Joseph, Abbot of Alaverdi, Georgia (09-15).jpg
Venerable Joseph, Abbot of Volokolamsk, Volotsk (09-09).jpg
Venerable Kyriakos the Anchorite (09-29).jpg
Venerable Lazarus of Murom (03-08).jpg
Venerable Leonid of Ustnedumsk (07-17).jpg
Venerable Leontios of Achaia (12-10).jpg
Venerable Leontius of the Kiev Far Caves (06-18).jpg
Venerable Longinus of Koryazhemsk, Vologda (02-10).jpg
Venerable Longinus, Wonderworker of Yarenga, Solovki (07-03).jpg
Venerable Luke of Hellas (02-07).jpg
Venerable Luke of Sicily (11-06).jpg
Venerable Luke the New Stylite of Chalcedon (12-11).jpg
Venerable Luke the Steward of the Kiev Caves (11-06).jpg
Venerable Macarius of Alexandria (01-19).jpg
Venerable Macarius of Zhabyn the Wonderworker (01-22).jpg
Venerable Macarius the Deacon of the Kiev Caves (01-19).jpg
Venerable Macarius the Faster, Abbot of the Khakhuli Monastery (12-21).jpg
Venerable Macarius the Great of Egypt (01-19).jpg
Venerable Macarius the Wonderworker, Abbot of Kalyazin (03-17).jpg
Venerable Macarius, Archimandrite of Ovruch (05-13).jpg
Venerable Macarius, Wonderworker of Zhabynka and Belev (09-22).jpg
Venerable Macrina, sister of Saint Basil the Great (07-19).jpg
Venerable Makarios the Roman of Novgorod (01-19).jpg
Venerable Makarios, Abbot of Zheltovod and Unzha (07-25).jpg
Venerable Makarius of Corinth (04-17).jpg
Venerable Marina and Kyra of Syria (02-28).jpg
Venerable Mark the Anchorite of Athens (04-05).jpg
Venerable Maron the Hermit of Syria (02-14).jpg
Venerable Martha, mother of Saint Simeon Stylites (09-01).jpg
Venerable Martha, mother of Venerable Simeon Stylites the Younger (07-04).jpg
Venerable Martinian, Abbot of Belozersk (01-12).jpg
Venerable Martyrius of Zelenets, Pskov (03-01).jpg
Venerable Martyrius, Abbot of Zelenets, Pskov (11-11).jpg
Venerable Mary (who was called Marinus), and her father, Venerable Eugene, at Alexandria (02-12).jpg
Venerable Mary of Egypt (04-01).jpg
Venerable Matrona, Abbess of Constantinople (11-09).jpg
Venerable Maximus the Confessor (01-21).jpg
Venerable Maximus the Greek (01-21).jpg
Venerable Melania the Younger of Rome (12-31).jpg
Venerable Memnon the Wonderworker (04-29).jpg
Venerable Methodius, Abbot of Peshnosha (06-14).jpg
Venerable Michael Maleinos (07-12).jpg
Venerable Michael of Parekhi (05-27).jpg
Venerable Michael the Fool-for-Christ of the Klops Monastery, Novgorod (01-11).jpg
Venerable Moses of Optina (06-16).jpg
Venerable Moses the Ethiopian of Scete (08-28).jpg
Venerable Moses the Hungarian of the Kiev Near Caves (07-26).jpg
Venerable Moses, Ascetic of the Syrian Deserts (02-23).jpg
Venerable Neilos the Ascetic of Sinai (11-12).jpg
Venerable Nestor the Chronicler of the Kiev Caves (10-27).jpg
Venerable Nicander, Abbot of Gorodensk, Novgorod (11-04).jpg
Venerable Nicholas Sviatosha Prince of Chernigov, and Wonderworker of the Kiev Near Caves (10-14).jpg
Venerable Nicholas the Confessor, Abbot of Studion (02-04).jpg
Venerable Nicholas, Radiant Star of the Georgians (11-03).jpg
Venerable Niketas of the Kiev Caves, Far Caves, Bishop of Novgorod (01-31).jpg
Venerable Niketas the Confessor, Abbot of Medikion (04-03).jpg
Venerable Niketas the Stylite, Wonderworker of Pereyaslavl, Zalesski (05-24).jpg
Venerable Nikon of Optina (06-25).jpg
Venerable Nikon “Metanoeite,” the Preacher of Repentance (11-26).jpg
Venerable Nikon, Abbot of Radonezh, disciple of Venerable Sergius (11-17).jpg
Venerable Nikon, Abbot of the Kiev Far Caves (03-23).jpg
Venerable Nikēphóros of Mount Athos (05-04).jpg
Venerable Nilus the Myrrhgusher of Lavra of Mount Athos (05-07).jpg
Venerable Nilus the Myrrhgusher of Mount Athos (11-12).jpg
Venerable Niphon of Mount Athos (06-14).jpg
Venerable Nίkander Wonderworker of Pskov (09-24).jpg
Venerable Onuphrius the Great (06-12).jpg
Venerable Onuphrius the Silent and Venerable Onesimos the Recluse, of the Kiev Caves (07-21).jpg
Venerable Onuphrius, Abbot of Malsk, Pskov (06-12).jpg
Venerable Pachomius the Great, Founder of Coenobitic Monasticism (05-15).jpg
Venerable Paisios Velichkovsky (11-15).jpg
Venerable Paisius of Hilandar, Bulgaria (06-19).jpg
Venerable Paisius of the Kiev Far Caves (07-19).jpg
Venerable Paisius the Great (06-19).jpg
Venerable Paisius, Abbot of Uglich (06-06).jpg
Venerable Paphnutius, Abbot of Borov (05-01).jpg
Venerable Patapius of Thebes (12-08).jpg
Venerable Paul of Thebes (01-15).jpg
Venerable Paul the Obedient, of the Kiev Caves (09-10).jpg
Venerable Paul the Simple of Egypt (10-04).jpg
Venerable Paul the Simple, disciple of Venerable Anthony the Great (03-07).jpg
Venerable Paul, Abbot of Obnora, Vologda (01-10).jpg
Venerable Paul, founder of the Xeropotamou Monastery on Mount Athos (07-28).jpg
Venerable Pelagia the Penitent (10-08).jpg
Venerable Peter of Mount Athos (06-12).jpg
Venerable Pharmuthius the Anchorite of Egypt (04-11).jpg
Venerable Pimen the Bulgarian of the Zographou Monastery, Mount Athos (11-03).jpg
Venerable Pimen the Faster of the Kiev Caves (08-07).jpg
Venerable Pimen the Great (08-27).jpg
Venerable Pimen the Much-Ailing of the Kiev Near Caves (08-07).jpg
Venerable Polychronius, Ascetic of the Syrian Deserts (02-23).jpg
Venerable Prince Andrew, in Monasticism Joasaph, of Kubensk, Vologda (09-10).jpg
Venerable Prochorus of Pcinja (10-19).jpg
Venerable Prochorus of the Kiev Near Caves (02-10).jpg
Venerable Prokopios the Confessor of Decapolis (02-27).jpg
Venerable Publius of Egypt (04-05).jpg
Venerable Romanus the Melodist, “Sweet-Singer” (10-01).jpg
Venerable Rufus the Obedient of the Kiev Far Caves (04-08).jpg
Venerable Sabbatius, Wonderworker of Solovki (09-27).jpg
Venerable Sabiana, Abbess of the Samtskhe Monastery (12-31).jpg
Venerable Savva the Recluse of the Kiev Far Caves (04-24).jpg
Venerable Savva the Sanctified (12-05).jpg
Venerable Savva, Abbot of Vishera, Novgorod (10-01).jpg
Venerable Savva, Igoumen of Zvenigorod, Disciple of Venerable Sergius of Radonezh (12-03).jpg
Venerable Schemamonk Cyril and Schemanun Maria, the parents of Saint Sergius of Radonezh (01-18).jpg
Venerable Sebastian Dabovich (11-30).jpg
Venerable Seraphim of Vyritsa (03-21).jpg
Venerable Serapion the Wonderworker, Abbot of Saint John the Baptist Monastery (08-24).jpg
Venerable Sergius (Srebryansky), the New Confessor of Tver (03-23).jpg
Venerable Sergius and Herman, Wonderworkers of Valaam (06-28).jpg
Venerable Sergius, Abbot of Nurma, disciple of Venerable Sergius of Radonezh, Vologda (10-07).jpg
Venerable Shio Mgvime (02-09).jpg
Venerable Shio Mgvime (03-03).jpg
Venerable Silouan of Mount Athos (09-24).jpg
Venerable Silvanus the Schemamonk of the Kiev Far Caves (07-10).jpg
Venerable Simeon of Emessa the Fool-For-Christ, and his fellow ascetic Venerable John (07-21).jpg
Venerable Simeon Stylites the Younger of Wonderful Mountain (05-24).jpg
Venerable Simeon the New Theologian (03-12).jpg
Venerable Simeon the Wonderworker (09-04).jpg
Venerable Simon the Myrrh-gusher of Mount Athos (12-28).jpg
Venerable Simon, Abbot of Volomsk (07-12).jpg
Venerable Sisoes the Great (07-06).jpg
Venerable Sophia of Ainos (06-04).jpg
Venerable Stephen (in monasticism Simeon), the Myrrhgusher and Prince of Serbia (02-13).jpg
Venerable Stephen of Komel, Abbot of Ozersk Monastery, Vologda (06-12).jpg
Venerable Stephen of Saint Savva Monastery (07-13).jpg
Venerable Stephen, Abbot of Khenolakkos Monastery, near Chalcedon (01-14).jpg
Venerable Stephen, Abbot of Makhrishche, Vologda (07-14).jpg
Venerable Stephen, Abbot of the Kiev Far Caves, and Bishop of Vladimir, in Volhynia (04-27).jpg
Venerable Stephen, Wonderworker, Abbot of Triglia (03-28).jpg
Venerable Stylianus of Paphlagonia (11-26).jpg
Venerable Sylvester, Abbot of Obnora (04-25).jpg
Venerable Synkletika of Alexandria (01-05).jpg
Venerable Thalelaios the Hermit of Syria (02-27).jpg
Venerable Theoctistus (09-03).jpg
Venerable Theodora of Alexandria (09-11).jpg
Venerable Theodora of Thessalonica (04-05).jpg
Venerable Theodore of Sanaxar (02-19).jpg
Venerable Theodore the Confessor, Abbot of the Studion (11-11).jpg
Venerable Theodore the Sanctified, disciple of Venerable Pachomius the Great (05-16).jpg
Venerable Theodore the Silent of the Kiev Caves (02-17).jpg
Venerable Theodore Trichinas “the Hair-Shirt Wearer” and Hermit Near Constantinople (04-20).jpg
Venerable Theodosius of the Kiev Far Caves (09-02).jpg
Venerable Theodosius the Great, the Cenobiarch (01-11).jpg
Venerable Theodosius, Abbot of the Kiev Far Caves Monastery, and Founder of Coenobitic Monasticism in Russia (05-03).jpg
Venerable Theodosius, Abbot of Totma, Vologda (01-28).jpg
Venerable Theonas, Archbishop of Thessalonica (04-04).jpg
Venerable Theophanes of Docheiariou, Mount Athos (08-19).jpg
Venerable Theophanes the Confessor of Sigriane (03-12).jpg
Venerable Theophanes the Merciful of Gaza (09-29).jpg
Venerable Therapon, Abbot of Monza (05-27).jpg
Venerable Therapon, Abbot of White Lake (05-27).jpg
Venerable Tikhon of Kaluga Or Medin (06-16).jpg
Venerable Tikhon of Luchov, Kostroma (06-16).jpg
Venerable Timothy of Symbola in Bithynia (02-21).jpg
Venerable Titus the Presbyter of the Kiev Near Caves (02-27).jpg
Venerable Titus the Soldier, of the Kiev Caves (02-27).jpg
Venerable Titus the Wonderworker (04-02).jpg
Venerable Tryphon, Abbot of Pechenga (12-15).jpg
Venerable Vitalius of Gaza (04-22).jpg
Venerable Xenia of Rome, and her two female servants (01-24).jpg
Venerable Xenophon, Abbot of Robeika, Novgorod (06-28).jpg
Venerable Xenophon, his wife, Mary, and their two sons, Arcadius and John, of Constantinople (01-26).jpg
Venerable Zachariah the Ascetic of the Kiev Caves (03-24).jpg
Venerable Zebinas, Ascetic of the Syrian Deserts (02-23).jpg
Venerable Zosimas of Palestine (04-04).jpg
Venerable Zosimas, Abbot of Solovki (04-17).jpg
Venerable Zosimas, Abbot of Vorbozomsk (04-04).jpg
Venerable Νikόdēmos, Abbot of Kozhe Lake (07-03).jpg
Veneration of the Precious Chains of the Holy and All-Glorious Apostle Peter (01-16).jpg
Vil'na Icon of the Mother of God (02-15).jpg
Virgin Martyr Agnes of Rome (01-21).jpg
Virgin Martyr Anysia at Thessalonica (12-30).jpg
Virgin Martyr Cecilia and the Holy Martyrs Valerian, Tiburtius and Maximus at Rome (11-22).jpg
Virgin Martyr Dorothy at Caesarea, in Cappadocia, and those with her (02-06).jpg
Virgin Martyr Eulalia of Barcelona and the Martyr Felix (08-22).jpg
Virgin Martyr Euphrasia of Nicomedia (01-19).jpg
Virgin Martyr Eupraxia of Tabenna (07-25).jpg
Virgin Martyr Fausta, and Martyrs Evilasius and Maximus, at Cyzicus (02-06).jpg
Virgin Martyr Febronia of Nisibis (06-25).jpg
Virgin Martyr Glyceria at Heraclea (05-13).jpg
Virgin Martyr Irais (Rhais) of Alexandria (09-23).jpg
Virgin Martyr Irais (Rhais) of Antinoe in Egypt (03-05).jpg
Virgin Martyr Julia of Carthage (07-16).jpg
Virgin Martyr Juliana of Nicomedia, and 500 men and 130 women with her (12-21).jpg
Virgin Martyr Lucy of Syracuse (12-13).jpg
Virgin Martyr Pelagia of Antioch (10-08).jpg
Virgin Martyr Pelagia of Tarsus, in Asia Minor (05-04).jpg
Virgin Martyr Pherbutha (Phermoutha) of Persia, with her sister, and servant (04-04).jpg
Virgin Martyr Seraphima (Serapia) of Antioch (07-29).jpg
Virgin Martyr Syra of Persia (08-24).jpg
Virgin Martyr Theodosia the Nun of Constantinople (05-29).jpg
Virgin Martyrs Agape, Irene and Chionia, in Illyria (04-16).jpg
Virgin Martyrs Ennatha, Valentina and Paula, of Palestine (02-10).jpg
Virgin Martyrs Martha and Mary, and their brother Lycarion, in Egypt (02-06).jpg
Virgin Martyrs Zenaΐda and Philonίlla, of Tarsus in Cilicia (10-11).jpg
vladimir-of-kiev.jpg
Weeping “Tikhvin” Icon of the Mother of God on Mount Athos (02-17).jpg
Yelets Icon of the Mother of God (01-11).jpg
“All-Merciful Kykkiotisa” Icon of the Mother of God (11-12).jpg
“Arapet” Icon of the Mother of God (09-06).jpg
“Assuage My Sorrows” Icon of the Mother of God (10-09).jpg
“Bethlehem” Icon of the Mother of God (12-26).jpg
“Bogolyubov” Icon of the Mother of God (06-18).jpg
“Chernigov-Gethsemane” Icon of the Mother of God (09-01).jpg
“Chukhloma” Icon of the Mother of God from Galich (07-20).jpg
“Consolation in Afflictions and Sorrows” Icon of the Mother of God (11-19).jpg
“Conversational” Icon of the Mother of God (08-14).jpg
“Czestochowa” Icon of the Mother of God (03-06).jpg
“Deliverer” Icon of the Mother of God (04-04).jpg
“Economissa” Icon of the Mother of God (07-05).jpg
“Enlightener of Minds” Icon of the Mother of God (08-15).jpg
“It Is Truly Meet” (“Axion Estin”) Icon of the Mother of God (07-13).jpg
“Jerusalem” Icon of the Mother of God (10-12).jpg
“Joy of All Who Sorrow” Icon of the Mother of God (10-24).jpg
“Joyful” Icon of the Mother of God (11-07).jpg
“Kiev-Bratsk” Icon of the Mother of God (05-10).jpg
“Kozel'shchansk” Icon of the Mother of God (02-21).jpg
“Kursk-Root” Icon of the Mother of God (11-27).jpg
“Maximov” Icon of the Mother of God (04-18).jpg
“Mirozh” Icon of the Mother of God (09-24).jpg
“Multiplier of Wheat” Icon of the Mother of God (10-15).jpg
“Neamts” Icon of the Mother of God (06-26).jpg
“O All-Hymned Mother” Icon of the Mother of God (10-06).jpg
“Our Lady of Sitka” Icon of the Mother of God (07-08).jpg
“Ozerianka” Icon of the Mother of God of Shuiu-Smolensk (11-02).jpg
“Pskov-Protection” Icon of the Mother of God (10-01).jpg
“Quick to Hear” Icon of the Mother of God (11-09).jpg
“Reigning” Icon of the Mother of God (03-02).jpg
“Saint Peter of Moscow” Icon of the Mother of God (08-24).jpg
“Seven Lakes” Icon of the Mother of God (06-26).jpg
“Seven Lakes” Icon of the Mother of God (07-28).jpg
“Staro Rus” Old Russian Icon of the Mother of God (05-04).jpg
“Support of Humble” Icon of the Mother of God (09-16).jpg
“Svena” Icon of the Mother of God (05-03).jpg
“Sweet-Kissing” Icon of the Mother of God of Smolensk (03-19).jpg
“Tenderness” Icon of the Mother of God (10-07).jpg
“Tenderness” Icon of the Mother of God from the Pskov Caves (05-21).jpg
“Tenderness” Icon of the Mother of God in Novgorod (07-08).jpg
“Tenderness” Icon of the Mother of God of the Pskov Caves (06-23).jpg
“The Healer” Icon of the Mother of God (09-18).jpg
“The Sign” Icon of the Mother of God (10-27).jpg
“Unburnt Bush” Icon of the Mother of God (09-04).jpg
“Unexpected Joy” Icon of the Mother of God (05-01).jpg
“Unexpected Joy” Icon of the Mother of God (12-09).jpg
“Unfading Flower” Icon of the Mother of God (04-03).jpg
“Vladimir” Icon of the Mother of God of Seliger (12-07).jpg
“Yaroslavl-Caves” Icon of the Mother of God (05-14).jpg
